<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.1 20151215//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Front Plant Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Front Plant Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Front. Plant Sci.</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Frontiers in Plant Science</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1664-462X</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Frontiers Media S.A.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">5491850</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpls.2017.01120</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Plant Science</subject><subj-group><subject>Original Research</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Genome-Wide Identification and Analysis of Genes, Conserved between <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> Rice Cultivars, that Respond to Low-Temperature Stress at the Vegetative Growth Stage</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>Manu</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://loop.frontiersin.org/people/231090/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Gho</surname><given-names>Yun-Shil</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>Ki-Hong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn001"><sup>*</sup></xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://loop.frontiersin.org/people/92907/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Seong-Ryong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn001"><sup>*</sup></xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://loop.frontiersin.org/people/257466/overview"/></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><sup>1</sup><institution>Department of Life Sciences, Sogang University</institution><country>Seoul, South Korea</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><sup>2</sup><institution>Graduate School of Biotechnology and Crop Biotech Institute, Kyung Hee University</institution><country>Yongin, South Korea</country></aff><author-notes><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Edited by: <italic>Harkamal Walia, University of Nebraska Lincoln, United States</italic></p></fn><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Reviewed by: <italic>Kazuo Nakashima, Japan International Research Center for Agricultural Sciences, Japan; Ratna Karan, University of Florida, United States</italic></p></fn><corresp id="fn001">*Correspondence: <italic>Seong-Ryong Kim, <email xlink:type="simple">sungkim@sogang.ac.kr</email> Ki-Hong Jung, <email xlink:type="simple">khjung2010@khu.ac.kr</email></italic></corresp><fn fn-type="other" id="fn002"><p>This article was submitted to Plant Abiotic Stress, a section of the journal Frontiers in Plant Science</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>30</day><month>6</month><year>2017</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2017</year></pub-date><volume>8</volume><elocation-id>1120</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>20</day><month>3</month><year>2017</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>09</day><month>6</month><year>2017</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017 Kumar, Gho, Jung and Kim.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2017</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Kumar, Gho, Jung and Kim</copyright-holder><license xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) or licensor are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p>Cold stress is very detrimental to crop production. However, only a few genes in rice have been identified with known functions related to cold tolerance. To meet this agronomic challenge more effectively, researchers must take global approaches to select useful candidate genes and find the major regulatory factors. We used five Gene expression omnibus series data series of Affymetrix array data, produced with cold stress-treated samples from the NCBI Gene Expression Omnibus (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/</ext-link>), and identified 502 cold-inducible genes common to both <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> rice cultivars. From them, we confirmed that the expression of two randomly chosen genes was increased by cold stress <italic>in planta</italic>. In addition, overexpression of <italic>OsWRKY71</italic> enhanced cold tolerance in &#x02018;Dongjin,&#x02019; the tested <italic>japonica</italic> cultivar. Comparisons between <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> rice, based on calculations of plant survival rates and chlorophyll fluorescence, confirmed that the <italic>japonica</italic> rice was more cold-tolerant. Gene Ontology enrichment analysis indicate that the &#x02018;<sc>L</sc>-phenylalanine catabolic process,&#x02019; within the Biological Process category, was the most highly overrepresented under cold-stress conditions, implying its significance in that response in rice. MapMan analysis classified &#x02018;Major Metabolic&#x02019; processes and &#x02018;Regulatory Gene Modules&#x02019; as two other major determinants of the cold-stress response and suggested several key <italic>cis</italic>-regulatory elements. Based on these results, we proposed a model that includes a pathway for cold stress-responsive signaling. Results from our functional analysis of the main signal transduction and transcription regulation factors identified in that pathway will provide insight into novel regulatory metabolism(s), as well as a foundation by which we can develop crop plants with enhanced cold tolerance.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>abiotic stress</kwd><kwd>cold stress</kwd><kwd>MapMan analysis</kwd><kwd>meta-expression analysis</kwd><kwd>Gene Ontology enrichment analysis</kwd><kwd>transcriptomics</kwd><kwd>rice</kwd><kwd>microarray</kwd></kwd-group><counts><fig-count count="9"/><table-count count="1"/><equation-count count="0"/><ref-count count="141"/><page-count count="20"/><word-count count="0"/></counts></article-meta></front><body><sec><title>Introduction</title><p>Agronomic productivity is declining due to various environmental problems, including cold stress. Crop yields are not sustainable when threatened by either chilling or freezing. The typical physiological response of a rice (<italic>Oryza sativa</italic>) plant exposed to such conditions is inhibited germination, followed by retarded seedling growth and restricted photosynthesis. Long periods of stress lead to chlorosis and tissue necrosis. Therefore, it is important that researchers improve their understanding of the regulatory mechanisms that can enhance cold tolerance.</p><p>The process of stress responses comprises perception of the low temperature, signal transduction, activation of TFs and stress-responsive genes, detoxification of reactive oxygen species (ROS), and initiation of repair systems. These steps make plants more tolerant to cold stress. Genetic and molecular studies have elucidated the functions of 59 such genes, for which information is now well-summarized in the OGRO database<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn01">1</xref></sup> (<xref rid="B122" ref-type="bibr">Yamamoto et al., 2012</xref>). Many important crops, including rice, are sensitive to low temperatures and do not easily acclimatize during periods of cold stress. At the seedling stage, rice is more vulnerable, even to mild chilling. This can reduce overall growth and disrupt and delay the cycle of crop maturation, eventually decreasing yields (<xref rid="B131" ref-type="bibr">Zhang et al., 2014</xref>). The challenge of global warming means that crop plants, including rice, will be more exposed to extreme growing environments, e.g., low and high temperatures. Although the response by rice to cold stress has been described (<xref rid="B138" ref-type="bibr">Zhi-guo et al., 2014</xref>; <xref rid="B103" ref-type="bibr">Wang D. et al., 2016</xref>; <xref rid="B84" ref-type="bibr">Shakiba et al., 2017</xref>), we still need to identify more effective genes that can regulate this response.</p><p>Transcriptome analysis is a very powerful tool that provides the global view of a phenomenon and frequently suggests novel candidate genes for further study. Such analyses have been conducted to improve our understanding about the cold-stress response in rice. For example, (<xref rid="B132" ref-type="bibr">Zhang T. et al., 2012</xref>) have found more than 500 candidate genes that are significantly up-regulated under low temperatures. Moreover, 183 DEGs related to cold stress have been identified by <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">Chawade et al. (2013)</xref>, 383 DEGs by <xref rid="B125" ref-type="bibr">Yang et al. (2015)</xref>, and more than 2000 DEGs by <xref rid="B136" ref-type="bibr">Zhao et al. (2014)</xref>. Nevertheless, it has been difficult to determine from publicly available transcriptome data which of these candidate genes show consistent expression patterns under stress as well as across a range of cultivars.</p><p>Here, we focused on genes that are consistently up-regulated between <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> cultivars under cold stress at the seedling stage. Our investigation utilized a large set of transcriptome data consisting of 27 <italic>japonica</italic> and 36 <italic>indica</italic> comparisons under low-temperature conditions, as obtained from the NCBI GEO (<xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">Barrett et al., 2011</xref>). From this, we identified 502 candidate genes that we further analyzed for their biological significance using GO term enrichment analysis and functional classifications via MapMan analysis<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn02">2</xref></sup>. We also selected two genes and confirmed their cold-inducible expression patterns using promoter-GUS trap systems. Based on those results, we proposed a novel promoter for further research applications to enhance cold tolerance. We then developed a hypothetical model to describe the signaling and transcriptional regulatory pathways that process the response to cold stress in rice.</p></sec><sec sec-type="materials|methods" id="s1"><title>Materials and Methods</title><sec><title>Plant Materials and Stress Treatments</title><p>Plants of <italic>japonica</italic> rice cv. Dongjin (&#x02018;DJ&#x02019;) and <italic>indica</italic> rice &#x02018;IR64&#x02019; (&#x02018;IR64&#x02019;) were grown in a walk-in chamber (Koencon, Hanam, South Korea) under conditions of 30&#x000b0;C [200 &#x003bc;mol m<sup>-2</sup> s<sup>-1</sup> (day)]/22&#x000b0;C (night) and a 12-h photoperiod for 10 days in plastic boxes containing 100 g of soil used in growing rice (Punong, Kyung-Ju, Korea) (<xref rid="B52" ref-type="bibr">Kumar et al., 2017</xref>). The effects of cold stress (exposure at 4&#x000b0;C) on the light intensity 110 &#x003bc;mol m<sup>-2</sup> s<sup>-1</sup> were examined after exposure to cold stress for 0, 24 h/1 day, 48 h/2 days, 72 h/3 days, 96 h/4 days, 120 h/5 days, and 144 h/6 days using chlorophyll fluorescence. Our mock treatment comprised a group of plants that remained at the normal growing temperature (28&#x000b0;C) throughout the experimental period. To observe the physiological features of these seedlings, we used samples collected before cold stress was induced, as well as from plants after 4 days of stress, and then after recovery under normal conditions for 5 days. Fresh weights (FWs) were recorded after recovery from cold stress, and dry weights (DWs) were measured after the samples were dried at 80&#x000b0;C for 2 days.</p></sec><sec><title>RT and qRT-PCR Analysis</title><p>For monitoring the expression of cold-inducible marker genes, seedlings (selected at 10 DAG, or 10 DAG) were hydroponically cultured in Yoshida solution and exposed to 4&#x000b0;C for 0, 1, 3, 6, 12, or 24 h. Primers of <italic>OsZFP182/LOC_Os03g60560</italic> and <italic>OsWYRKY71/LOC_Os02g08440</italic> were used for RT and qRT-PCR analyses at a final concentration of 10 pmol, with 3 &#x003bc;L (equivalent to 30 ng of total RNA) of cDNA as template (Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM2">S1</xref>). The internal controls were primers of rice <italic>ubiquitin 5</italic> (Os<italic>Ubi5</italic>) and rice <italic>actin 1</italic> (<italic>RAc1</italic>) (Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM2">S1</xref>). An RNeasy Mini Plant Kit (Qiagen, Germany) was used for total RNA isolation and an RT Complete Kit (Biofact, Korea) was used for cDNA synthesis according to the manufacturers&#x02019; instructions. Primers were designed with Gene Runner software<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn03">3</xref></sup> and NCBI primer blast<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn04">4</xref></sup>. The amplified products were resolved on a 1% agarose gel.</p></sec><sec><title>Measurement of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub></title><p>An uptake assay was conducted to determine the relative concentration of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, using Amplex<sup>&#x000ae;</sup> Red reagent (10-acetyle-3, 7dihydroxyphenoxazine; Molecular Probes/Invitrogen, United States) (<xref rid="B68" ref-type="bibr">Mohanty et al., 1997</xref>). Leaf tissues (0.1 mg &#x003bc;L<sup>-1</sup>) were homogenized in a standard MS medium (<xref rid="B70" ref-type="bibr">Murashige and Skoog, 1962</xref>) and then incubated under darkness for 30 min with horseradish peroxidase (0.2 U mL<sup>-1</sup>) and Amplex<sup>&#x000ae;</sup> Red reagent (1 &#x003bc;M). The H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> released from these tissues was detected by a SpectraMax 250 Microplate Reader (Molecular Devices Inc., United States) with absorbance measured at 560 nm (<xref rid="B53" ref-type="bibr">Kumar et al., 2014</xref>).</p></sec><sec><title>Meta-Expression Analysis</title><p>We downloaded raw data for five GSE data series (i.e., GEO accession number <ext-link ext-link-type="DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank" xlink:href="GSE6901">GSE6901</ext-link>, <ext-link ext-link-type="DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank" xlink:href="GSE33204">GSE33204</ext-link>, <ext-link ext-link-type="DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank" xlink:href="GSE37940">GSE37940</ext-link>, <ext-link ext-link-type="DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank" xlink:href="GSE38023">GSE38023</ext-link>, and <ext-link ext-link-type="DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank" xlink:href="GSE31077">GSE31077</ext-link>) that are related to cold-stress responses, as indicated from the NCBI GEO<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn05">5</xref></sup> (<xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">Barrett et al., 2011</xref>). Details are presented in Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM3">S2</xref>. The data were normalized using an Affy Package encoded by R language, and the intensity values were transformed into the log<sub>2</sub> scale as we have previously described (<xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">Cao et al., 2012</xref>). This allowed us to generate log<sub>2</sub> fold-change values for cold-stressed samples. Similar fold-changes were revealed for other stress conditions. For each data series, we used those fold-change data to perform a KMC analysis to identify genes that were consistently up-regulated under all cold-stress conditions. The KMC analysis of meta-expression data for abiotic stresses &#x02013; salt, drought, cold, heat, submergence, and anaerobic conditions &#x02013; grouped all of the candidate genes into 12 clusters. From these, we selected 502 genes that were up-regulated by cold-stress treatment but not during the recovery period. Heatmap images were produced using Mev software (<xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">Chu et al., 2008</xref>).</p></sec><sec><title><italic>GUS</italic> Assays and Co-segregation Test of Promoter Trap Lines</title><p>To examine <italic>GUS</italic> expression patterns, we germinated seeds from two promoter trap lines in an MS medium for 7 days. These lines were obtained from a mixed pool of PFG T-DNA tagging lines from POSTECH in Korea (<xref rid="B55" ref-type="bibr">Lee et al., 2004</xref>; <xref rid="B44" ref-type="bibr">Jung et al., 2005</xref>, <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>, <xref rid="B45" ref-type="bibr">2015</xref>; <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">Hong et al., 2017</xref>; <xref rid="B112" ref-type="bibr">Wei et al., 2017</xref>). The resultant plantlets were then exposed to cold stress (4&#x000b0;C) for 0 or 24 h. Afterward, whole seedlings from all treatment groups were soaked for 8 h in a <italic>GUS</italic>-staining solution before their roots were photographed with a camera (Canon EOS 550D; Cannon, Tokyo, Japan).</p></sec><sec><title>Analysis of <italic>Cis</italic>-Regulatory Elements</title><p>To identify any consensus CREs in the promoters of our cold-inducible genes, we extracted 2-kb upstream sequences of ATG for <italic>LOC_Os01g31370</italic> and <italic>LOC_Os03g49830</italic>, which were validated in our current <italic>GUS</italic> assays. We also used the sequence for <italic>LOC_Os10g41200</italic>, which was previously reported to be a cold-inducible promoter based on the promoter-<italic>GUS</italic> system (<xref rid="B79" ref-type="bibr">Rerksiri et al., 2013</xref>; <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">Jeong and Jung, 2015</xref>) from PLANTPAN<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn06">6</xref></sup> (<xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">Chang et al., 2008</xref>). Several MEME searches were performed with those sequences in the FASTA format via the Web server hosted by the National Biomedical Computation Resource<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn07">7</xref></sup>. We looked for up to five CREs with an option of 12 maximum motif widths. Using the MAST, we then searched DNA sequences for matches to the putative TOMTOM within a set of promoter sequences (<xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">Bailey et al., 2006</xref>).</p></sec><sec><title>Analysis of Gene Ontology Enrichment</title><p>To analyze the biological significance of selected candidate genes, we employed the GO enrichment tool installed in the Rice Oligonucleotide Array Database<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn08">8</xref></sup> (<xref rid="B42" ref-type="bibr">Jung et al., 2008a</xref>; <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">Cao et al., 2012</xref>). For this, we uploaded 502 genes showing upregulation in both <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> cultivars under cold stress. A fold-enrichment value higher than the standard (&#x02018;1&#x02019;) meant that the selected GO term was over-represented more than was expected. Terms with &#x0003e;2-fold enrichment values and <italic>p</italic>-values &#x0003c; 0.05 were also used as criteria for choosing the most significant GO terms in the &#x02018;Biological Process&#x02019; category.</p></sec><sec><title>MapMan Analysis</title><p>The rice MapMan classification system covers 36 BINs, each of which can be extended in a hierarchical manner into subBINs (<xref rid="B98" ref-type="bibr">Usadel et al., 2005</xref>; <xref rid="B96" ref-type="bibr">Urbanczyk-Wochniak et al., 2006</xref>). By applying diverse MapMan tools, a significant gene list selected from high-throughput data analysis can be integrated to diverse overviews. Here, we uploaded locus IDs from the RGAP for 502 DEGs with a value of &#x02018;3,&#x02019; which indicated upregulation under cold stress. Finally, we used four overviews &#x02013; Metabolism, Regulation, Transcription, and Proteasome &#x02013; installed in the MapMan toolkit.</p></sec><sec><title>Analysis of Rice Genes with Known Functions</title><p>To evaluate the functional significance of our candidate genes, we compared our list with the one from OGRO, which summarizes rice genes with known functions (<bold>Table <xref ref-type="table" rid="T1">1</xref></bold>; <xref rid="B122" ref-type="bibr">Yamamoto et al., 2012</xref>).</p><table-wrap id="T1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Rice genes functionally characterized as cold-inducible.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="5"><thead><tr><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Gene</th><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Major_F</th><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Minor_F</th><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">RAP-DB_ID</th><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MSU_ID</th><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Method</th><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Detailed functions</th><th valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reference</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1C</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0127100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g03670.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>ZFP182</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0820300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g60560.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">Huang et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1B</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0522000</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g35010.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1A</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0522200</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g35030.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY45</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0322900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g25770.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T; ABA sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B92" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY71</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0181300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g08440.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al., 2016</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsTPP1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0661100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g44230.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">Ge et al., 2008</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY76</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0417600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g25060.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe oryzae</italic>; cold T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B126" ref-type="bibr">Yokotani et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMYB2</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0315400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g20090.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T; ABA sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B124" ref-type="bibr">Yang et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCAF1B</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0684900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g58810.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">Chou et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMAPK5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0285800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g17700.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic> and <italic>Burkholderia glumae</italic>; cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B118" ref-type="bibr">Xiong and Yang, 2003</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsbZIP52/RISBZ5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0662200</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g45140.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold and drought T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B59" ref-type="bibr">Liu et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsSPX1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0603600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g40120.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold and oxidative stresses T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B102" ref-type="bibr">Wang C. et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1C</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0127100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g03670.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>ZFP182</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0820300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g60560.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">Huang et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsSRO1c</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0230300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g12820.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Stomatal control; oxidative stress R.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B127" ref-type="bibr">You et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1B</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0522000</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g35010.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1A</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0522200</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g35030.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY45</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0322900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g25770.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T; ABA sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B92" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMYB2</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0315400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g20090.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T; ABA sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B124" ref-type="bibr">Yang et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsbHLH148</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0741100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g53020.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B83" ref-type="bibr">Seo et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCAF1B</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0684900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g58810.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">Chou et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMAPK5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0285800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g17700.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic> and <italic>Burkholderia glumae</italic>; cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B118" ref-type="bibr">Xiong and Yang, 2003</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsbZIP52/RISBZ5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0662200</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g45140.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold and drought T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B59" ref-type="bibr">Liu et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>ONAC045</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os11g0127600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os11g03370.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B137" ref-type="bibr">Zheng et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCDPK7</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0584600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g49510.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B80" ref-type="bibr">Saijo et al., 2000</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCPK4</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0126400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g03410.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Protection of cellular membrane from drought stress.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">Campo et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsERF3</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0797600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g58420.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T by controlling ethylene biosynthesis.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B101" ref-type="bibr">Wan et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsAP2-39</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0610400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g52090.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; fertility; and drought T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B120" ref-type="bibr">Yaish et al., 2010</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1C</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0127100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g03670.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsEATB</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0457900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g28440.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Internode elongation; panicle branching; tillering; salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B75" ref-type="bibr">Qi et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>ZFP182</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0820300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g60560.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">Huang et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>ZFP179</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0839100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g62190.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity and oxidative stress T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B89" ref-type="bibr">Sun et al., 2010</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1B</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0522000</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g35010.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDREB1A</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0522200</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g35030.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY45</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0322900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g25770.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T; ABA sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B92" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsTPP1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0661100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g44230.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">Ge et al., 2008</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMYB2</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0315400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g20090.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold, drought, and salinity T; ABA sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B124" ref-type="bibr">Yang et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMAPK5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0285800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g17700.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic> and <italic>Burkholderia glumae</italic>; cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B118" ref-type="bibr">Xiong and Yang, 2003</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>ONAC045</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os11g0127600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os11g03370.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B137" ref-type="bibr">Zheng et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCDPK7</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0584600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g49510.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Drought and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B80" ref-type="bibr">Saijo et al., 2000</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCPK4</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0126400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g03410.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Protection of cellular membrane from salt stress.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">Campo et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsPLDbeta1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Blast R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os10g0524400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os10g38060.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Pyricularia grisea</italic> and <italic>Xanthomonas oryzae</italic> pv. <italic>oryzae</italic>.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B121" ref-type="bibr">Yamaguchi et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY45</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Blast R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0322900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g25770.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Xanthomonas oryzae</italic> pv. <italic>oryzae</italic>, pv. <italic>oryzicola</italic>, and <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic>.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B92" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsAOS2</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Blast R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0225900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g12500.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic>.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B64" ref-type="bibr">Mei et al., 2006</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY76</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Blast R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0417600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g25060.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe oryzae</italic>; cold T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B126" ref-type="bibr">Yokotani et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMAPK5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Blast R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0285800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g17700.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic> and <italic>Burkholderia glumae</italic>; cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B118" ref-type="bibr">Xiong and Yang, 2003</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsbHLH65</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Blast R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0493100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g41570.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Defense R against rice blast.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B86" ref-type="bibr">Shin et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY45</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bacterial blight R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0322900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g25770.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Xanthomonas oryzae</italic> pv. <italic>oryzae</italic>, pv. <italic>oryzicola</italic>, and <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic>.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B92" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY76</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bacterial blight R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0417600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g25060.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Xanthomonas oryzae</italic> pv. <italic>oryzae</italic>.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B126" ref-type="bibr">Yokotani et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMAPK5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bacterial blight R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0285800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g17700.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic> and <italic>Burkholderia glumae</italic>; cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B118" ref-type="bibr">Xiong and Yang, 2003</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsNAC4</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bacterial blight R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0816100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g60020.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bacterial blight R; HR cell death.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B46" ref-type="bibr">Kaneda et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY71</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Bacterial blight R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0181300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g08440.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Xanthomonas oryzae</italic> pv. <italic>oryzae</italic>.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B60" ref-type="bibr">Liu et al., 2007</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsHI-LOX</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Insect R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os08g0508800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os08g39840.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to rice striped stem borer and rice brown planthopper.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B139" ref-type="bibr">Zhou et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY45</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sheath blight R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0322900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g25770.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Xanthomonas oryzae</italic>, <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic> and <italic>Rhizoctonia solani</italic>.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B92" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMAPK5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other disease R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0285800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g17700.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R to <italic>Magnaporthe grisea</italic> and <italic>Burkholderia glumae</italic>; cold, drought, and salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B118" ref-type="bibr">Xiong and Yang, 2003</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsSRO1c</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other stress R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0230300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g12820.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Apoplastic and chloroplastic oxidative stress T; temperature stress T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B127" ref-type="bibr">You et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCAF1B</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other stress R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0684900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g58810.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Wounding; ABA T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">Chou et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsSPX1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other stress R</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0603600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g40120.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cold and oxidative stress T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B102" ref-type="bibr">Wang C. et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>ZFP179</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other soil stress T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0839100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g62190.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Salinity and oxidative stress T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B89" ref-type="bibr">Sun et al., 2010</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsSPX1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">R/T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Other soil stress T</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0603600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g40120.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Phosphate homeostasis.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B102" ref-type="bibr">Wang C. et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsEATB</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0457900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g28440.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Internode elongation; panicle branching; tillering; salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B75" ref-type="bibr">Qi et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsPHI-1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0757100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g52040.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Aya et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMPS</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0618400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g40530.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grain size; total biomass.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B82" ref-type="bibr">Schmidt et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>RERJ1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0301500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g23550.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; JA sensitivity during seedling stage.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">Kiribuchi et al., 2004</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>GA2ox3</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0757200</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g55240.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; gibberellin catabolism.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B62" ref-type="bibr">Lo et al., 2008</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>TIFY11b</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0181100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g08330.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grain size; plant height.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B29" ref-type="bibr">Hakata et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsDOG</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os08g0504700</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os08g39450.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; cell elongation; regulation of gibberellin biosynthesis.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B61" ref-type="bibr">Liu et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsBZR1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os07g0580500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os07g39220.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; leaf angle; brassinosteroid sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Bai et al., 2007</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>gid1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0407500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g33730.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; gibberellin sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B95" ref-type="bibr">Ueguchi-Tanaka et al., 2005</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>cZOGT1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0556500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g46980.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; leaf senescence; crown root.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B51" ref-type="bibr">Kudo et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>brd1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0602300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g40540.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; brassinosteroid biosynthesis.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B69" ref-type="bibr">Mori et al., 2002</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCPK4</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0126400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g03410.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">Campo et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsAP2-39</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0610400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g52090.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; fertility; drought T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B120" ref-type="bibr">Yaish et al., 2010</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>RERJ1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Shoot seedling</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0301500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g23550.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; JA sensitivity during seedling stage.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">Kiribuchi et al., 2004</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>CYP85A1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Shoot seedling</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0602300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g40540.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Rice lamina bending and leaf unrolling by promoting castasterone (CS).</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">Asahina et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>kch1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Shoot seedling</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os12g0547500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os12g36100.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Coleoptile elongation.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">Frey et al., 2010</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsWRKY42</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Culm leaf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0462800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g26430.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Promotion of leaf senescence through ROS accumulation; plant death.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">Han et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsEATB</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Culm leaf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0457900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g28440.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Internode elongation; panicle branching; tillering; salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B75" ref-type="bibr">Qi et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsPHI-1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Culm leaf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0757100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g52040.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cell size and number in culm (increased number of smaller parenchyma cells)</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Aya et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsBZR1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Culm leaf</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os07g0580500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os07g39220.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; leaf angle; brassinosteroid sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Bai et al., 2007</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsIAA23</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Root</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0597000</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g39590.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Root development; quiescent center identity; auxin sensitivity.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B71" ref-type="bibr">Ni et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>MAIF1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Root</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0671100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g44990.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Seed germination; ABA sensitivity; root growth.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B123" ref-type="bibr">Yan et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>EL5</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Root</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0559800</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g35329.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Maintenance of cell viability of root primordia.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B50" ref-type="bibr">Koiwai et al., 2007</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>cZOGT1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Root</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0556500</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g46980.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; leaf senescence; crown root.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B51" ref-type="bibr">Kudo et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCPK4</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Root</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0126400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g03410.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Regulation of Na+ accumulation.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">Campo et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Rdd1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Seed</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0264000</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g15900.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grain length and width; 1000-grain weight; flowering time.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">Iwamoto et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsMPS</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Seed</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0618400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g40530.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grain size; total biomass.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B82" ref-type="bibr">Schmidt et al., 2013</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>TIFY11b</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Seed</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os03g0181100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os03g08330.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grain size; plant height.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B29" ref-type="bibr">Hakata et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsEATB</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Panicle flower</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os09g0457900</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os09g28440.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Internode elongation; panicle branching; tillering; salinity T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B75" ref-type="bibr">Qi et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>MSF1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Panicle flower</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os05g0497200</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os05g41760.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Spikelet determinacy; floral organ development.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B78" ref-type="bibr">Ren et al., 2016</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsAP2-39</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sterility</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0610400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g52090.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dwarfism; fertility; drought T.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B120" ref-type="bibr">Yaish et al., 2010</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsCHR4</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Source activity</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os07g0497000</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os07g31450.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chloroplast development in adaxial mesophyll.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B135" ref-type="bibr">Zhao et al., 2012</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>BE1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Source activity</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0726400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g51084.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Starch granule-binding, amylopectin structure.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">Abe et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>MAIF1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germination dormancy</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os02g0671100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os02g44990.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Seed germination; ABA sensitivity; root growth.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B123" ref-type="bibr">Yan et al., 2011</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>PLD&#x003b2;1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Germination dormancy</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os10g0524400</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os10g38060.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Sensitivity to ABA during germination stage.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B57" ref-type="bibr">Li and Xue, 2007</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Rdd1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Flowering</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0264000</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g15900.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Grain length and width; 1000-grain weight; flowering time.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">Iwamoto et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>etr2</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Flowering</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0169100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g08740.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Flowering time; ethylene sensitivity; stem starch content.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B115" ref-type="bibr">Wuriyanghan et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>SPK1(SYG1)</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PT</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os06g0603600</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os06g40120.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Pi-dependent inhibitor of Phosphate starvation response regulator 2 (PHR2).</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B111" ref-type="bibr">Wang et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>AFT</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0185300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g09010.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Kd</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Ester-linked ferulate content in cell walls.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B74" ref-type="bibr">Piston et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>etr2</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os04g0169100</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os04g08740.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Mutant</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Flowering time; ethylene sensitivity; stem starch content.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B115" ref-type="bibr">Wuriyanghan et al., 2009</xref></td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>OsExo1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Others</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Os01g0777300</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>LOC_Os01g56940.1</italic></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">OX</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Processing of double-strand break sites.</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">Kwon et al., 2012</xref></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><attrib><italic>R, resistant; T, tolerant; MT, morphological trait; OX, overexpression; Kd, knockdown</italic>.</attrib></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec><title>Evaluation of Cold Tolerance in a Line Over-Expressing <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic></title><p>Plants from an Ox line for <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic> (<italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox) under the control of CaMV35S promoter (<xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al., 2016</xref>) and from the WT (<italic>Japonica</italic> cv. <italic>Dongjin</italic>) were grown for 10 days in plastic boxes containing soil. To test their tolerance, we then exposed them to cold stress (4<sup>o</sup>C) for 5 days and then returned them to normal growing conditions for 6 days of recovery. Survival rates were determined at the end of this experimental period. Cold stress analysis of <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox lines was done with three replicates.</p></sec></sec><sec><title>Results and Discussion</title><sec><title>Physiological Responses of Cold-Stressed Rice Seedlings</title><p>Cold stress adversely affects plant growth and yield, and rice isparticularly susceptible at the seedling stage (<xref rid="B131" ref-type="bibr">Zhang et al., 2014</xref>). Ouranalysis involved 10-day-old &#x02018;DJ&#x02019; (<italic>japonica</italic>) and &#x02018;IR64&#x02019;(<italic>indica</italic>) plants exposed to 4&#x000b0;C for 4 days.Afterward, they recovered for 5 days at 28&#x000b0;C. Their phenotypes are shown in <bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1A</xref></bold>. At the end of this experimental period, the survival rate was 30.5% for &#x02018;DJ&#x02019; versus 0.0% for &#x02018;IR64,&#x02019;indicating that the former was more old-tolerant (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1B</xref></bold>). The <italic>F</italic><sub>W</sub> value was 162 mg higher for &#x02018;DJ&#x02019; while its DW was 29 mg higher than for &#x02018;IR64&#x02019; (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1C</xref></bold>). Prolonged cold stress also negatively affected photosynthetic efficiency, with both cultivars showing significant reductions after 24 h (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1D</xref></bold>). The decline in efficiency after 48 h was more severe for &#x02018;IR64&#x02019; than for &#x02018;DJ.&#x02019;</p><fig id="F1" position="float"><label>FIGURE 1</label><caption><p>Analysis of cold stress responses by <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> rice cultivars. <bold>(A)</bold> Phenotypes associated with cold-stress response by &#x02018;DJ&#x02019; and &#x02018;IR64&#x02019; rice seedlings observed during treatment for 4 days followed by 5 days of recovery. <bold>(B)</bold> Tolerance of seedlings based on survival rates. <bold>(C)</bold> Fresh and dry weights after recovery from cold stress. <bold>(D)</bold> Photosynthetic efficiency (<italic>F</italic><sub>v</sub>/<italic>F</italic><sub>m</sub>) after cold treatment for 4 days. <bold>(E)</bold> Determination of ROS concentrations (i.e., levels of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>) in seedlings after cold treatment for 24 h. <bold>(F)</bold> Expression of 2 marker genes (<italic>OsZFP182</italic> and <italic>OsWRKY71</italic>) in stressed seedlings, using <italic>OsUbi5</italic> as an internal control. <sup>&#x02217;&#x02217;&#x02217;</sup>, <italic>p</italic>-value &#x0003c; 0.001, <sup>&#x02217;&#x02217;</sup>, 0.001&#x0003c; <italic>p</italic>-value &#x0003c; 0.01; <sup>&#x02217;</sup>, 0.01 &#x0003c; <italic>p</italic>-value &#x0003c; 0.05.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g001"/></fig><p>The accumulation of ROS, including H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, is a major indicator of the plant response to various abiotic stresses. We found that &#x02018;IR64&#x02019; had higher H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> concentrations than did &#x02018;DJ&#x02019; after 3 and 24 h of cold treatment (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1E</xref></bold>).</p><p>We also evaluated the expression patterns of two well-known cold stress-responsible genes, <italic>OsZFP182</italic> and <italic>OsWRKY71</italic> (<xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">Huang et al., 2007</xref>; <xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al., 2016</xref>) and found that, as expected, their expression was significantly induced, and to nearly the same extent, in both cultivars (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1F</xref></bold>). This demonstrated that the tool of global transcriptome data can be broadly applied for determining and, ultimately, improving cold tolerance in rice.</p></sec><sec><title>Genome-Wide Identification of Cold Stress-Inducible Genes in Both <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> Cultivars Using Meta-Expression Data Analysis</title><p>As a quantitative trait, tolerance to cold stress is governed by different sets of genes, and through diverse mechanisms. We used meta-expression analysis with transcriptome data and downloaded information about global candidate genes from the NCBI GEO for series GSE37940 and GSE38023 (<xref rid="B129" ref-type="bibr">Zhang F. et al., 2012</xref>; <xref rid="B130" ref-type="bibr">Zhang H. et al., 2012</xref>). After normalizing these data, we generated 63 comparisons for cold-stress treatment, as well as 49 comparisons for drought stress, 6 for high temperatures, and 4 for submergence (Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM3">S2</xref>). Our KMC analysis with the resultant fold-change data revealed 502 genes that were significant up-regulated upon cold stress but not under recovery conditions (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">2</xref></bold>). From this, we prepared 27 comparisons with two <italic>japonica</italic> cultivars &#x02013; &#x02018;C418&#x02019; (a <italic>japonica</italic> restorer line for hybrid rice production and cold sensitive) and &#x02018;Li-Jiang-Xin-Tuan-Hei-Gu&#x02019; (&#x02018;LTH,&#x02019; cold tolerant genotype) &#x02013; and 36 comparisons with five <italic>indica</italic> cultivars &#x02013; &#x02018;IR24&#x02019; (photoperiod-insensitive, high yielding and cold sensitive variety), &#x02018;IR64&#x02019; [variety with moderate tolerance toward toxicity in response to various molecules including salt, alkali, iron, and boron as well as deficiencies in phosphorus and zinc, but sensitivity to cold stress], &#x02018;K354&#x02019; (a BC2F6 introgression line as a progeny of C418 and cold tolerant variety), &#x02018;Huahui 1&#x02019; (&#x02019;HH1,&#x02019; insect-resistant variety as a progeny of Minghui 63), and &#x02018;Minghui 63&#x02019; (&#x02018;MH,&#x02019; heat tolerant variety and a parental line of HH1). Their upregulation was conserved between <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> cultivars. All of these genes provide potential for a broader range of applications to enhance cold tolerance in rice. These 502 DEGs were used for further analysis of the cold-stress response (Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM4">S3</xref>).</p><fig id="F2" position="float"><label>FIGURE 2</label><caption><p>Heatmap of genes up-regulated under stress in both <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> cultivars. Panel above heatmap indicates type of abiotic stress applied; parentheses indicate number of stress/control in each treatment. Panel below heatmap shows detailed information for &#x0201c;main target&#x0201d; samples under cold stress. Gray box, <italic>indica</italic> cultivars; black, <italic>japonica</italic> cultivars; blue, cold stress/control; and brown, recovery/control. <italic>Indica</italic> cultivars: &#x02018;IR64,&#x02019; &#x02018;Huahui 1&#x02019; (&#x02018;HH1&#x02019;), &#x02018;Minghui 63&#x02019; (&#x02018;MH&#x02019;), &#x02018;K354,&#x02019; and &#x02018;IR24&#x02019;; <italic>japonica</italic> cultivars: &#x02018;C418&#x02019; and &#x02018;Li-Jiang-Xin-Tuan-Hei-Gu&#x02019; (&#x02018;LTH&#x02019;).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g002"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Validation of Cold-Inducible Genes in Rice Roots Using the <italic>GUS</italic> Reporter System and qRT-PCR</title><p>Promoter traps employing the <italic>GUS</italic> reporter gene system have been used to identify promoters involved in regulating tissue-specific and stress-responsive expression patterns (<xref rid="B44" ref-type="bibr">Jung et al., 2005</xref>, <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>). Our meta-expression analysis identified the top 50 genes showing &#x0003e;3.5-fold upregulation by cold stress when compared with the control (Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM4">S3</xref>). We then searched and identified 52 potential promoter trap lines of 43 candidate genes and examined <italic>GUS</italic> expression patterns in 7-day-old seedlings. The lines for two genes (<italic>PFG 3A-50649</italic> for <italic>LOC_Os01g31370</italic> and <italic>PFG 1C-08613</italic> for <italic>LOC_Os03g49830</italic>) displayed <italic>GUS</italic> expression in the roots after plants were exposed to stress for 24 h (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">3</xref></bold> and Supplementary Figure <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">S1</xref>). This cold-related expression was also verified by qRT-PCR (<bold>Supplementary Figure <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">S1</xref></bold>). Previous studies using a promoter-<italic>GUS</italic> vector or promoter trap system have confirmed the upregulation of <italic>LOC_Os10g41200</italic> in response to cold stress (<xref rid="B87" ref-type="bibr">Su et al., 2010</xref>; <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">Jeong and Jung, 2015</xref>). Our findings demonstrated that the promoter trap system, when combined with qualified genome-wide transcriptome data, is a very effective way for quickly identifying the activity of an endogenous promoter. This enables researchers to develop novel promoters for future applications.</p><fig id="F3" position="float"><label>FIGURE 3</label><caption><p>Validation of expression patterns for two cold stress-responsive genes using GUS reporter systems. Promoter trap lines using <italic>GUS</italic> reporter gene were selected and tested for GUS activity. Promoter trap line for <italic>LOC_Os01g31370</italic>, Line PFG 3A-50649 (right), and that of <italic>LOC_Os03g49830</italic>, Line PFG 1<italic>C</italic>-08613 (left) were confirmed through co-segregation test of <italic>GUS</italic> expression and T-DNA insertion through genotyping analysi<italic>s.</italic> Upper panel, GUS-staining data from promoter trap lines under normal growing conditions; lower panel, lines under cold-stress conditions. Homozygous progeny of T-DNA insertion for each of two lines were used.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g003"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Analysis of <italic>Cis</italic>-Regulatory Elements Conserved in Promoters of Three Cold-Inducible Genes Confirmed by the <italic>GUS</italic> Reporter System</title><p>To identify the <italic>cis</italic>-regulatory regulatory elements (CREs) associated with the response to cold, we used promoter regions in 2-kb sequences upstream of ATG of the two cold-inducible genes (<italic>LOC_Os01g31370</italic> and <italic>LOC_Os03g49830)</italic> that had been validated through GUS trap assays and also included the promoter region of <italic>LOC_Os10g41200</italic>, which have previously been reported as a cold-inducible gene using GUS reporter systems (<xref rid="B87" ref-type="bibr">Su et al., 2010</xref>; <xref rid="B79" ref-type="bibr">Rerksiri et al., 2013</xref>; <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">Jeong and Jung, 2015</xref>). Through <italic>in silico</italic> analysis of CREs, we revealed the presence of common 51 CREs in the promoter regions from the PLANTPAN 2.0 database<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn09">9</xref></sup> (<xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">Chow et al., 2016</xref>) and MEME tool<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="fn010">10</xref></sup> (<xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">Bailey et al., 2006</xref>). Selected promoter regions and CREs are summarized in Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM5">S4</xref>. Of these, we have more interest in five unique CREs: DRECRTCOREAT (RCCGAC), ABREMOTIFIOSRAB16B (AGTACGTGGC), ABADESI2 (GGACGCGTGGC), GARE2OSREP1 (TAACGTA), and ANAERO3CONSENSUS (TCATCAC) (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">4</xref></bold> and Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM5">S4</xref>). DRECRTCOREAT is a core motif of dehydration-responsive element/C-repeat (DRE/CRT) found in the promoters of genes from various species. Previous studies reported that <italic>OsDREB1A, AtDREB1A</italic> and <italic>ZmDREB1A</italic> bound to (G/ACCGAC) with the different efficiency by competitive DNA binding assays (<xref rid="B81" ref-type="bibr">Sakuma et al., 2002</xref>; <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">Dubouzet et al., 2003</xref>; <xref rid="B76" ref-type="bibr">Qin et al., 2004</xref>) and <italic>OsDREB</italic> gene encodes transcription activators that function in drought, salt and cold-responsive gene expression (<xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">Dubouzet et al., 2003</xref>). However, although the Aloe DREB1 can bind to the DRE, it may also bind to other CREs effectively, which can function in a new cold-induced signal transduction pathway (<xref rid="B108" ref-type="bibr">Wang and He, 2007</xref>). It has been known that phytohormones including ABA, auxin, gibberellic acid (GA), salicylic acid (SA) and ethylene are related to the cold responses positively or negatively (<xref rid="B65" ref-type="bibr">Miura and Furumoto, 2013</xref>; <xref rid="B100" ref-type="bibr">Verma et al., 2016</xref>). Among the ABA-responsive CREs, we found that ABREMOTIFIOSRAB16B and ABADESI2 earlier identified from rice <italic>Osrab16B</italic> promoter and wheat histone H3 promoter were related to ABA-regulated transcription (<xref rid="B93" ref-type="bibr">Terada et al., 1993</xref>; <xref rid="B73" ref-type="bibr">Ono et al., 1996</xref>; <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">Busk and Pag&#x000e8;s, 1998</xref>). In addition, GARE1OSREP1 is involved in Gibberellin-responsive element (GARE) found in rice Os<italic>REP-1</italic> promoter (<xref rid="B72" ref-type="bibr">Ogawa et al., 2003</xref>; <xref rid="B90" ref-type="bibr">Sutoh and Yamauchi, 2003</xref>). ANAERO3CONSENSUS found in promoters of anaerobic genes is involved in the fermentative pathway and related to anaerobic response (<xref rid="B67" ref-type="bibr">Mohanty et al., 2005</xref>). In summary, DRECRTCOREAT might be related to cold-preferred expression, and ABREMOTIFIOSRAB16B, ABADESI2 and GARE1OSREP1 might be associated with crosstalk between phytohormones and cold stress-preferred expression. The other CREs not mentioned here might have novel roles in driving cold stress-preferred expression and further experiments will be required to clarify our estimation.</p><fig id="F4" position="float"><label>FIGURE 4</label><caption><p>Identification of CREs conserved in three cold-inducible genes. Consensus CREs in promoters of cold-inducible genes were studied with GUS reporter systems, using 2-kb upstream sequences of ATG for <italic>LOC_Os01g31370</italic>, <italic>LOC_Os03g49830</italic>, and LOC_Os10g41200 to confirm cold induction <italic>in planta</italic>. <bold>(A)</bold> Distribution of five CREs conserved in promoters of three cold-inducible genes but not in those of randomly selected genes. <bold>(B)</bold> Names and conserved sequences presented using MEME suit. <bold>(C)</bold> Positions and frequency were determined for five CREs in promoters of above three genes.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g004"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Analysis of GO Enrichment Reveals Biological Processes Associated with Cold Stress Responses in Rice Roots</title><p>To determine the functions of 502 DEGs up-regulated by cold stress in rice roots, we studied their GO terms within the &#x02018;biological process&#x02019; category. In all, 15 terms were highly over-represented in our gene list, with <italic>p</italic>-values &#x0003c; 0.05 and fold-enrichment values of &#x0003e;2-fold (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F5">5</xref></bold> and Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM6">S5</xref>). We have also previously reported this (<xref rid="B41" ref-type="bibr">Jung et al., 2008b</xref>). The terms included &#x02018;<sc>L</sc>-phenylalanine catabolic process&#x02019; (19.9-fold enrichment), &#x02018;response to water&#x02019; (16.2), &#x02018;phenylpropanoid metabolic process&#x02019; (15.6), &#x02018;oxylipin biosynthetic process&#x02019; (12.9), &#x02018;activation of protein kinase C activity by GPCRP signaling pathway&#x02019; (9.7), &#x02018;phospholipid metabolic process&#x02019; (8.1), &#x02018;gibberellin metabolic process&#x02019; (7.3), &#x02018;response to stress&#x02019; (7.1), &#x02018;lipid catabolic process &#x02019; (6.1), &#x02018;protein amino acid dephosphorylation&#x02019; (5.3), &#x02018;trehalose biosynthetic process&#x02019; (5.2), &#x02018;cytochrome complex assembly&#x02019; (4.7), &#x02018;lipid biosynthetic process&#x02019; (4.4), &#x02018;regulation of transcription&#x02019; (3.2), and &#x02018;protein ubiquitination&#x02019; (3.2).</p><fig id="F5" position="float"><label>FIGURE 5</label><caption><p>Gene Ontology enrichment analysis in &#x02018;Biological Process&#x02019; category for genes up-regulated in response to cold stress. In all, 15 GO terms were over-represented by &#x0003e;2-fold enrichment value, with <italic>p</italic>-values &#x0003c; 0.05. Details of GO assignment are presented in Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM5">S4</xref>.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g005"/></fig><p>Of these, &#x02018;<sc>L</sc>-phenylalanine catabolic process&#x02019; was the most significantly enriched by cold stress while another critical component in that response was &#x02018;phenylpropanoid metabolic process.&#x02019; Transcriptome profile analysis of maize (<italic>Zea mays</italic>) seedlings in response to cold stress has shown that 31 DEGs for phenylalanine metabolism are induced (<xref rid="B85" ref-type="bibr">Shan et al., 2013</xref>). Transcript and metabolic profiling of <italic>Arabidopsis thaliana</italic> (<xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">Charlton et al., 2008</xref>) has indicated that phenylpropanoids, along with Lys, Met, Trp, Tyr, Arg, Cys, and the polyamine biosynthetic pathway, are important metabolites that are highly accumulated in response to cold stress. Profiling of maize seedling transcripts by <xref rid="B85" ref-type="bibr">Shan et al. (2013)</xref> has also revealed the induction of 54 DEGs for phenylpropanoid metabolism. All of these results suggest that the phenylpropanoid metabolic pathway is activated when various plant species are exposed to cold stress.</p><p>Metabolic profiling of <italic>Camellia sinensis in</italic> response to cold (<xref rid="B107" ref-type="bibr">Wang X.C. et al., 2013</xref>) has shown that expression is increased for genes involved in the signal transduction mechanism. Three oxylipin biosynthetic-related genes and two trehalose biosynthetic genes are highly expressed in cold-tolerant <italic>Elymus nutans</italic> (<xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">Fu et al., 2016</xref>). Moreover, transcriptomics profiling of <italic>Lotus japonicus</italic> under cold stress has demonstrated that those conditions lead to the upregulation of the phospholipid metabolic process (<xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Calzadilla et al., 2016</xref>).</p><p>Transcriptome profiling has presented the upregulation of GA metabolism in cold-stressed &#x02018;Meyer&#x02019; zoysiagrass (<xref rid="B113" ref-type="bibr">Wei et al., 2015</xref>) and greater than threefold induction of <italic>gibberellin 2-beta-dioxygenase</italic> genes in cassava, which is also related to responses to abiotic and biotic stimuli (<xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">An et al., 2012</xref>). All of these reports indicate that the gibberellin metabolic pathway is activated during periods of cold stress.</p><p>Genes for &#x02018;lipid catabolic process,&#x02019; &#x02018;protein amino acid dephosphorylation,&#x02019; &#x02018;cytochrome complex assembly,&#x02019; &#x02018;regulation of transcription,&#x02019; and &#x02018;protein ubiquitination&#x02019; also have important roles in the abiotic-stress response (see, e.g., data in <bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F5">5</xref></bold>). For example, in <italic>A. thaliana</italic>, several lipid catabolism enzymes in rice (in particular, phospholipids A and D) are activated by low temperatures, as manifested by the heightened accumulation of fatty acids (<xref rid="B106" ref-type="bibr">Wang et al., 2006</xref>; <xref rid="B97" ref-type="bibr">Usadel et al., 2008</xref>). Serine phosphorylation or dephosphorylation is involved in cold activation signaling of <italic>Arabidopsis ICE1</italic>, and its Ox in <italic>Isatis tinctoria</italic> confers cold tolerance (<xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">Chinnusamy et al., 2003</xref>; <xref rid="B116" ref-type="bibr">Xiang et al., 2013</xref>). <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">Campos et al. (2003)</xref> have reported that a cold-tolerant genotype of <italic>Coffea</italic> sp. copes with chilling through an enhanced lipid biosynthetic process. Regulation of transcription is also important for cold tolerance. For example, in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>, ICE1 and an R2R3-type MYB control the transcriptional regulation of <italic>DREB</italic> TFs within the mechanism for cold tolerance (<xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">Agarwal et al., 2006</xref>; <xref rid="B66" ref-type="bibr">Miura et al., 2007</xref>). We also identified &#x02018;Protein ubiquitination&#x02019; as another important GO term that is also linked with cold tolerance. For example, <italic>Arabidopsis HOS1</italic> mediates the ubiquitination and degradation of ICE1 and negatively regulates the response to cold stress (<xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">Dong et al., 2006</xref>). In summary, the biological processes that we identified here as being closely associated with the cold-stress response provide novel and informative resources for improving our knowledge about regulatory factors involved in the molecular mechanism(s) that enable plants to cope in a low-temperature environment.</p></sec><sec><title>MapMan Analysis of Cold-Related Genes in Rice Roots</title><p>The MapMan program is very effective for visualizing diverse overviews associated with high-throughput transcriptome data (<xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">Jung and An, 2012</xref>). We uploaded Locus IDs for 502 DEGs for the cold-stress response (Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM4">S3</xref>) to various overviews installed in that program. Among them, 79 elements were assigned to the &#x02018;RNA&#x02019; category, 58 to &#x02018;protein,&#x02019; 36 to &#x02018;signaling,&#x02019; 25 to &#x02018;miscellaneous function&#x02019; (&#x02018;misc&#x02019;), 22 to &#x02018;hormone metabolism,&#x02019; 17 to &#x02018;stress,&#x02019; 14 to &#x02018;development,&#x02019; 13 to &#x02018;transport,&#x02019; 10 each to &#x02018;lipid metabolism&#x02019; and &#x02018;cell wall,&#x02019; 7 to &#x02018;secondary metabolism,&#x02019; and a smaller number to other functional groups (Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM7">S6</xref>). Another 154 genes did not have assigned MapMan terms. In particular, the identification of 17 cold stress-regulated elements supports our proposal that they have potential significance for enhancing tolerance when our candidate genes are expressed.</p></sec><sec><title>Analysis of Metabolism Overview Associated with the Cold-Stress Response in Rice</title><p>To investigate the significant metabolic pathways involved in the response to cold stress, we analyzed the Metabolism overview associated with 502 DEGs (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F6">6</xref></bold>). Among the 44 elements found there, secondary metabolism included six for phenylpropanoids; nine for lipid metabolism, e.g., phospholipid biosynthesis and lipid degradation; 10 for cell wall metabolism, including cellulose synthase and modification; three for mitochondrial electron transport; seven for major carbohydrate (CHO) metabolism; four for minor CHO metabolism; as well as several others related to this stress, such as amino acid, nitrogen, and nucleotide metabolisms (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F6">6A</xref></bold> and Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM7">S6</xref>). These results implied that a rice plant triggers those metabolic pathways as part of its stress response. Similar to our findings from the GO enrichment analysis, &#x02018;<sc>L</sc>-phenylalanine catabolic process,&#x02019; &#x02018;<sc>L</sc>-phenylalanine metabolic process,&#x02019; and category &#x02018;secondary metabolism&#x02019; (including &#x02018;phenylpropanoid metabolism&#x02019;) were over-represented.</p><fig id="F6" position="float"><label>FIGURE 6</label><caption><p>MapMan analysis of rice genes associated with response to cold stress. Overviews of Metabolism <bold>(A)</bold>, Regulation <bold>(B)</bold>, Transcription <bold>(C)</bold>, and Ubiquitin-mediated protein degradation pathway <bold>(D)</bold> were mapped with selected cold-inducible genes. Red boxes, groups of genes up-regulated by cold stress. Details are presented in Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM7">S6</xref>.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g006"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Analyses of Regulation, Transcription, and Ubiquitin-Dependent Proteasome Pathway Overviews Associated with the Cold-Stress Response in Rice</title><p>Our Regulation overview of 502 DEGs demonstrated that 73 TFs, 30 genes related to protein modification, 21 associated with protein degradation, and 22 related to hormone metabolism were up-regulated in rice during periods of cold stress (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F6">6B</xref></bold>). Of these, the TFs were the most abundant, meaning that they are largely involved in regulating the response and tolerance of rice to such conditions. Therefore, those genes should be considered candidates for further study to regulate the cold-stress response in rice. Accordingly, we found 13 WRKY TFs, 10 MYB and four MYB-related TFs, 10 Apetala2/Ethylene Responsive Element Binding Proteins (AP2/EREBPs), five Basic Helix-Loop-Helix (bHLH) genes, five Constans (CO)-like zinc finger family TFs, five C2H2 zinc finger family TFs, and other TFs for this response (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F6">6C</xref></bold> and Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM7">S6</xref>).</p><p>In plants, the WRKY TFs have been more actively studied than others, and most of them have positive roles in the cold-stress response in various plant species, including <italic>Ipomoea batatas</italic>, where the function of a WRKY TF was first described (<xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">Ishiguro and Nakamura, 1994</xref>). This TF contains a WYRKY domain and a zinc-finger motif. <xref rid="B63" ref-type="bibr">Mar&#x000e8; et al. (2004)</xref> have reported the role of <italic>Hv-WRKY38</italic> in the cold-stress response by <italic>Hordeum vulgare</italic>, and Ox of <italic>WYRKY76</italic> and <italic>WYRKY71</italic> has been shown to increase cold tolerance in rice (<xref rid="B126" ref-type="bibr">Yokotani et al., 2013</xref>; <xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al., 2016</xref>). Likewise, Ox of <italic>CsWYRKY46</italic> in <italic>Cucumis sativus</italic> regulates tolerance to chilling and freezing (<xref rid="B134" ref-type="bibr">Zhang et al., 2016</xref>), and the cold-inducible <italic>BcWYRKY46</italic> from <italic>Brassica campestris</italic> enhances cold tolerance in transgenic tobacco (<italic>Nicotiana tabacum</italic>) (<xref rid="B104" ref-type="bibr">Wang et al., 2012</xref>). In contrast, Os<italic>WYRKY45</italic> and <italic>OsWRKY13</italic> negatively regulate cold tolerance in rice (<xref rid="B77" ref-type="bibr">Qiu et al., 2008</xref>; <xref rid="B92" ref-type="bibr">Tao et al., 2011</xref>), while <italic>WYRKY34</italic> mediates the cold sensitivity of mature pollen in <italic>A. thaliana</italic> (<xref rid="B141" ref-type="bibr">Zou et al., 2010</xref>) CsWRKY2, a novel <italic>WRKY</italic> gene from <italic>Camellia sinensis</italic>, is involved in cold stress responses (<xref rid="B109" ref-type="bibr">Wang Y. et al., 2016</xref>).</p><p>Like <italic>WRKY</italic> TFs, <italic>MYB</italic> TFs have important roles in cold tolerance. They include <italic>OsMYB4 OsMYB2</italic> and <italic>MYBS3</italic> in rice (<xref rid="B99" ref-type="bibr">Vannini et al., 2004</xref>; <xref rid="B87" ref-type="bibr">Su et al., 2010</xref>; <xref rid="B124" ref-type="bibr">Yang et al., 2012</xref>), <italic>MYB15</italic> and <italic>HOS10</italic> in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> (<xref rid="B140" ref-type="bibr">Zhu et al., 2005</xref>; <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">Agarwal et al., 2006</xref>), and <italic>GmMYBj1</italic> in soybean (<xref rid="B88" ref-type="bibr">Su et al., 2014</xref>); and <italic>TaMYB3R1</italic> in <italic>Triticum aestivum</italic> (<xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">Cai et al., 2015</xref>). Whereas all of those TFs have positive effects, <italic>MYBC1</italic> in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> negatively regulates cold tolerance (<xref rid="B128" ref-type="bibr">Zhai et al., 2010</xref>).</p><p>The AP2/EREBP TFs also enhance cold tolerance. They include <italic>JcDREB</italic>, <italic>JcCBF2</italic>, <italic>BnaERF-B3-hy15</italic>, <italic>DEAR1</italic>, <italic>ZmDREB1A</italic>, <italic>OsDREB1D</italic>, and <italic>ZmDBP4</italic> analyzed in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> (<xref rid="B76" ref-type="bibr">Qin et al., 2004</xref>; <xref rid="B94" ref-type="bibr">Tsutsui et al., 2009</xref>; <xref rid="B133" ref-type="bibr">Zhang et al., 2009</xref>; <xref rid="B105" ref-type="bibr">Wang et al., 2010</xref>, <xref rid="B111" ref-type="bibr">2014</xref>; <xref rid="B91" ref-type="bibr">Tang et al., 2011</xref>; <xref rid="B117" ref-type="bibr">Xiong et al., 2013</xref>); and <italic>JERF1</italic>, <italic>OsDREB1</italic>, and <italic>AtDREB1A</italic> in tobacco (<xref rid="B47" ref-type="bibr">Kasuga et al., 2004</xref>; <xref rid="B58" ref-type="bibr">Li et al., 2005</xref>; <xref rid="B114" ref-type="bibr">Wu et al., 2007</xref>).</p><p>A major TF family of other TFs involved in cold tolerance is bHLH. <italic>ICE1</italic>, <italic>ICE2</italic>, <italic>VabHLH1</italic>, and <italic>OrbHLH001</italic> analyzed in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> (<xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">Chinnusamy et al., 2003</xref>; <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">Fursova et al., 2009</xref>; <xref rid="B56" ref-type="bibr">Li et al., 2010</xref>; <xref rid="B119" ref-type="bibr">Xu et al., 2014</xref>) and <italic>OsbHLH1</italic> in rice (<xref rid="B110" ref-type="bibr">Wang et al., 2003</xref>) are involved in cold tolerance. Next, <italic>HOS1</italic>, a member of the CO-like zinc finger family, regulates cold tolerance in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> via <italic>CONSTANS</italic> degradation (<xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">Jung et al., 2012</xref>), while OsZFP245, a member of the C2H2 zinc finger family, confers such tolerance in rice (<xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">Huang et al., 2009</xref>).</p><p>Related to protein degradation, signal transduction, and hormone metabolism, a few studies have been conducted. Therefore, future analyses of uncharacterized TFs and the regulatory elements associated with protein degradation, signal transduction, and hormone metabolism identified in this study might shed the light on the effective methods for improving cold tolerance in rice.</p></sec><sec><title>Evaluation of Candidate Genes Associated with Cold Stress Using Rice Genes with Known Functions</title><p>To evaluate the significance of our candidate genes, we searched the literature to determine if functions for them have been reported previously. This was accomplished with the online OGRO database, which provides a thorough summary of rice genes that have been characterized through molecular and genetic techniques (<xref rid="B122" ref-type="bibr">Yamamoto et al., 2012</xref>). That summary presents the roles of 49 genes according to three agronomic trait categories: morphological, physiological, and resistance/tolerance. The functional identification of genes related to resistance/tolerance traits is the most abundant, with 27 genes being part of that category, including 12 genes involved in cold tolerance; 16, drought tolerance; 11, salinity tolerance; six, blast resistance; five, bacterial blight resistance; two, soil stress tolerance; one each for sheath blight resistance and insect resistance; and four for other stress resistances (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F7">7</xref></bold>). Of these, 17 genes are partially responsible for at least two traits in that resistance/tolerance category. <italic>OsMAPK5</italic> and <italic>OsWRKY45</italic> are involved in tolerance to both biotic stress (bacterial blight and blast) and abiotic stress (drought, salinity, and cold). Others include <italic>OsMYB2</italic>, <italic>ZFP182</italic>, <italic>OsDREB1A</italic>, <italic>OsDREB1B</italic>, and <italic>OsDREB1C</italic>, for responses to drought, salinity, and cold; <italic>OsbZIP52</italic>/RISBZ5 and <italic>OsCAF1B</italic>, cold and drought; <italic>OsTPP1</italic>, cold and salinity; and <italic>OsCPK4</italic>, <italic>OsCDPK7</italic>, and <italic>OsNAC045</italic>, drought and salinity. The results from our transcriptome analysis had also suggested that these last three are active in the cold-stress response. We found it interesting that genes induced by low temperatures also function in other abiotic-stress responses. This implies that regulation of those responses is very complex and that intensive crosstalk might occur among them.</p><fig id="F7" position="float"><label>FIGURE 7</label><caption><p>Distribution of functionally characterized genes according to three major agronomic categories. <italic>Y</italic>-axis, number of known genes; <italic>X</italic>-axis, minor functional categories in three major functional categories, presented in order of &#x0201c;Resistance or Tolerance,&#x0201d; &#x0201c;Morphological trait,&#x0201d; and &#x0201c;Physiological trait&#x0201d;.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g007"/></fig><p>Regarding morphological traits, 13 genes are related to dwarfism, five to rooting, four to culms/leaves, three to seeds, three to shoots/seedlings, two to panicles/flowers, and three to other plant components (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F7">7</xref></bold>). These results indicate that the cold stress-responsive genes studied here might also affect various traits, e.g., dwarfism, that can inhibit or delay normal growth. Regarding physiological traits, we found that two genes each are related to flowering, germination dormancy, and source activity, while one is related to sterility, and one to other traits (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F7">7</xref></bold>). Because our findings demonstrate an interaction between cold stress and diverse morphological/physiological traits, we suggest that future studies should screen mutants and focus on their morphological and physiological phenotypes while also screening phenotypes under cold-stress conditions.</p></sec><sec><title>Evaluating the Functional Significance of Cold-Inducible Genes Using a Gain-of-Function Mutant for <italic>OsWRKY71</italic></title><p>Among the cold-inducible genes identified in our study,<italic>OsWRKY71</italic> is induced by cold stress(<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1F</xref></bold>). As we have reported previously(<xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al., 2016</xref>), its Ox leads to cold tolerance(<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F8">8</xref></bold>). The survival rate is 19% higherfor <italic>OsWRKY71</italic>-Ox lines than for the WT, and the transgenics also have 30% higher FWs and 60% higher DWs. Estimating<italic>F</italic><sub>v</sub>/<italic>F</italic><sub>m</sub> values is a good way to depict photosynthetic efficiency under cold stress. Our data indicated that, after 96 h of chilling treatment, this efficiency in <italic>OsWRKY71</italic>-Ox lines decreased from 0.8 to 0.5 while that value in the WT declined from 0.8 to 0.3. Therefore, the Ox lines are 25% more efficient and <italic>OsWRKY71</italic> confers cold tolerance.</p><fig id="F8" position="float"><label>FIGURE 8</label><caption><p>Cold-stress response mediated by <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic> using Ox line. <bold>(A)</bold> Phenotype of response by <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox line observed after 10-DAG rice seedlings were exposed to cold treatment for 5 days, followed by 6 days of recovery. <bold>(B)</bold> Cold tolerance of <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox line, based on survival rates. <bold>(C)</bold> Fresh weights of <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox line compared with WT after recovery. <bold>(D)</bold> Dry weights of <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox line compared with WT after recovery. <bold>(E)</bold>
<italic>F</italic><sub>v</sub>/<italic>F</italic><sub>m</sub> rates compared between <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox line and WT during cold-stress period. <bold>(F)</bold> RT-PCR results for <italic>OsWYRKY71</italic>-Ox line and we used <italic>RAc1</italic> as an internal control.<sup>&#x02217;</sup>, 0.01 &#x0003c; <italic>p</italic>-value &#x0003c; 0.05.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g008"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Hypothetical Model for Regulating the Cold-Stress Response that Is Conserved between <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> Rice Cultivars</title><p>The response to low temperatures can be divided into four steps: perception of cold stress, signaling cascades for the response, regulation of gene expression, and protection from freezing damage. Our proposed model (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F9">9</xref></bold>) is based on published physiological and biochemical aspects as well as reports of functions for genes involved in the relevant signaling and transcriptional pathways.</p><fig id="F9" position="float"><label>FIGURE 9</label><caption><p>Overview of regulatory pathway for cold-stress signaling in rice. Signaling and transcriptional regulatory pathways for cold tolerance have four steps: cold perception (blue boxes), signaling cascades (green boxes), gene expression cascades (brown boxes)/protein degradation (light-brown boxes), and protection from cold (tolerance) through activation of target genes (pink boxes). Cold-inducible candidate genes were mapped to individual boxes and are presented as locus IDs. Red-colored locus IDs are genes previously characterized for cold-stress responses, with each name indicated either on left side or below corresponding ID. Brown-colored locus IDs are genes previously characterized but not directly linked with cold-stress response.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpls-08-01120-g009"/></fig><p>We theorize that the first reaction by a plant to chilling is to increase membrane rigidity. This is followed by the generation of ROS, then regulation of phosphate homeostasis and activation of calcium receptors and histidine kinases. The ensuing signal transduction cascades are coupled with signal perception. Examples include MAP kinase cascades and a two-component signaling system by histidine kinase. The former is more likely because the cascades of MAP kinase (OsMAPK5/LOC_Os03g17700.1), MAP kinase kinase (MAP2K; OsMKK4/LOC_Os02g54600.1), and MAP kinase kinase kinase (MAP3K, seven members in <bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F9">9</xref></bold>), are stimulated in response to cold stress, making them the most probable candidates for this pathway. Of them, it has been known that <italic>OsMAPK5</italic> positively regulates tolerance to cold temperatures and other sources of stress (<xref rid="B118" ref-type="bibr">Xiong and Yang, 2003</xref>).</p><p>For the latter possibility, the processes might be more complex. In response to cold, plants use Ca<sup>2+</sup> as a signal. Although we did not yet identify the histidine kinase genes in rice showing significant induction under cold stress, the signal received by a Ca<sup>2+</sup> channel might bind to a Ca<sup>2+</sup> sensor, such as calmodulin (CaM), and CaM-like protein might stimulate Ca<sup>2+</sup>/CaM-dependent protein kinases as suggested in <bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F9">9</xref></bold>. Thereafter, gene expression is regulated by TFs through a process that incorporates CBF/DREB-dependent or -independent pathways.</p><p>In the case of the CBF/DREB-dependent pathway, a signal from the map kinase cascades is recognized by ICE1, which encodes a bHLH TF that activates the expression of DREB genes in the downstream pathway by directly binding the promoter regions. This results in stimulation of cold stress-responsive genes that are required for altering cellular metabolism. OsbHLH148 or RERJ1 are probable candidate genes, having the same roles as ICE1 in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>, i.e., OsbHLH148 is involved in drought tolerance and RERJ1 functions in normal plant growth and development (<xref rid="B83" ref-type="bibr">Seo et al., 2011</xref>). OsDREB1A, OsDREB1B, and OsDREB1C have roles in tolerance to cold, drought, and salinity by triggering the expression of target genes (<xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Ito et al., 2006</xref>). Regarding the CRT/DREB-independent pathway, TFs such as OsWRKY71 (<xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al., 2016</xref>), OsWRKY76 (<xref rid="B126" ref-type="bibr">Yokotani et al., 2013</xref>), OsbZIP52 (<xref rid="B59" ref-type="bibr">Liu et al., 2012</xref>), ZFP182 (<xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">Huang et al., 2012</xref>), and OsMYB2 (<xref rid="B124" ref-type="bibr">Yang et al., 2012</xref>) are components of the trait for cold stress response. For example, a rice line that over-expressor of OsbZIP52 displays a cold-sensitive phenotype (<xref rid="B59" ref-type="bibr">Liu et al., 2012</xref>) and the application of such stress induces the expression of OsbZIP52, which then negatively affects the extent of that tolerance.</p><p>Although the functions of most genes for cold tolerance have not yet been defined, other types of TFs identified in our meta-expression and MapMan analyses might also be important for regulating tolerance, as indicated by the TF overview presented by MapMan (<bold>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F6">6</xref></bold> and Supplementary Table <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM7">S6</xref>).</p><p>Among other processes, HOS1, encoding the ring type E3 ligase, participates in the degradation process of ICE1 that is stimulated at low temperature, resulting in inactivation of the CRT/DREB-dependent transcription regulation pathway (<xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">Chinnusamy et al., 2003</xref>; <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">Dong et al., 2006</xref>). Likewise, OST1, encoding the well-known Ser /Thr protein kinase, is activated in response to cold and phosphorylates ICE1, leading to its stability and transcriptional activity (<xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">Ding et al., 2015</xref>). However, OST1 also hinders the interaction between HOS1 and ICE1, subsequently leading to the degradation of ICE1 under cold stress when HOS1 is suppressed. OsCAF1B, with RNase D activity, functions in post-transcriptional regulation and may affect various pathways for cold tolerance (<xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">Chou et al., 2014</xref>). OsTPP1 has a role in resistance to abiotic stress. At low temperatures, it also positively regulates the expression of tolerance genes by participating in the glucose deprivation signaling pathway (<xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">Ge et al., 2008</xref>). Despite these numerous reports, however, all of these hypotheses must still be verified through further experiments.</p><p>Cold stress is one of the main environmental factors that adversely affect plant growth and yield. Thus, it is important that we understand this stress signaling and its regulatory network if we are to develop cultivars with greater tolerance. To this end, we have produced a hypothetical model that considers our current findings as well as data derived from earlier research.</p></sec></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p>Our study goal was to identify low-temperature-responsive genes that can be commonly used by rice researchers throughout the world. For this, we collected a broad range of genome-wide transcriptome data produced from plants under low-temperature conditions. This information included data deposited from published microarrays or re-processed from RNA-seq analyses. The 502 genes identified here are conserved between <italic>japonica</italic> and <italic>indica</italic> cultivars, two representative subspecies of rice. Results of bioinformatics analyses using GO enrichment and MapMan tools for these candidate genes was applied to reveal important biological processes and related metabolic and regulatory pathways. In addition, we constructed a possible regulatory network based on such information. Serving as a valuable foundation for future research, our proposed model can help in the discovery of key regulatory genes that confer cold tolerance. This can be accomplished by using a gene-indexed mutant collection or biotechnological approaches that are well-established in rice.</p></sec><sec><title>Author Contributions</title><p>K-HJ, MK, and S-RK design overall experimental schemes. MK and Y-SG performed experiments. MK and K-HJ wrote manuscript.</p></sec><sec><title>Conflict of Interest Statement</title><p>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p></sec></body><back><ack><p>This work was supported by grants from the Next-Generation BioGreen 21 Program PJ01192701 to S-RK and Basic Science Research Program through the National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF) funded by the Ministry of Education (NRF-2016R1D1A1A09919568 to K-HJ, the Rural Development Administration, Republic of Korea.</p></ack><fn-group><fn id="fn01"><label>1</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://qtaro.abr.affrc.go.jp/ogro">http://qtaro.abr.affrc.go.jp/ogro</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn02"><label>2</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://mapman.gabipd.org">http://mapman.gabipd.org</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn03"><label>3</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.generunner.net/">http://www.generunner.net/</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn04"><label>4</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/tools/primer-blast/">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/tools/primer-blast/</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn05"><label>5</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/">http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo/</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn06"><label>6</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://plantpan2.itps.ncku.edu.tw/">http://plantpan2.itps.ncku.edu.tw/</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn07"><label>7</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.nbcr.net/">http://www.nbcr.net/</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn08"><label>8</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.ricearray.org/analysis/go_enrichment.shtml">http://www.ricearray.org/analysis/go_enrichment.shtml</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn09"><label>9</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://plantpan2.itps.ncku.edu.tw">http://plantpan2.itps.ncku.edu.tw</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn010"><label>10</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://meme-suite.org/">http://meme-suite.org/</ext-link></p></fn></fn-group><sec sec-type="supplementary material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><p>The Supplementary Material for this article can be found online at: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpls.2017.01120/full#supplementary-material">http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fpls.2017.01120/full#supplementary-material</ext-link></p><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SM1"><label>FIGURE S1</label><caption><p>Validation of expression patterns for three genes (LOC_Os03g49830, LOC_Os10g41200, and LOC_Os01g31370) under cold stress using qRT-PCR analysis. <sup>&#x02217;&#x02217;&#x02217;</sup>, <italic>p</italic>-value &#x0003c; 0.001.</p></caption><media xlink:href="Image_1.JPEG"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="S1"><media xlink:href="Image_1.JPEG"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SM2"><media xlink:href="Table_1.DOCX"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SM3"><media xlink:href="Table_2.DOCX"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SM4"><media xlink:href="Table_3.XLS"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SM5"><media xlink:href="Table_4.XLSX"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SM6"><media xlink:href="Table_5.XLSX"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SM7"><media xlink:href="Table_6.XLSX"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></sec><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="B1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Asai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yago</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Oitome</surname><given-names>N. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Crofts</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Relationships between starch synthase I and branching enzyme isozymes determined using double mutant rice lines.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMC Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>14</volume>:<issue>80</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1471-2229-14-80</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Agarwal</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kapoor</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>C.-H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fujii</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>A R2R3 type MYB transcription factor is involved in the cold regulation of CBF genes and in acquired freezing tolerance.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Biol. Chem.</italic></source>
<volume>281</volume>
<fpage>37636</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>37645</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.M605895200</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17015446</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Transcriptome profiling of low temperature-treated cassava apical shoots showed dynamic responses of tropical plant to cold stress.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMC Genomics</italic></source>
<volume>13</volume>:<issue>64</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-13-64</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Asahina</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tamaki</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sakamoto</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shibata</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Blue light-promoted rice leaf bending and unrolling are due to up-regulated brassinosteroid biosynthesis genes accompanied by accumulation of castasterone.</article-title>
<source><italic>Phytochemistry</italic></source>
<volume>104</volume>
<fpage>21</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>29</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.phytochem.2014.04.017</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24856112</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Aya</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hobo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sato-Izawa</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ueguchi-Tanaka</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kitano</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Matsuoka</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>A novel AP2-type transcription factor, SMALL ORGAN SIZE1, controls organ size downstream of an auxin signaling pathway.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>55</volume>
<fpage>897</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>912</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/pcp/pcu023</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24486766</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>M. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gampala</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>S. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>W. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chong</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>Functions of OsBZR1 and 14-3-3 proteins in brassinosteroid signaling in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A.</italic></source>
<volume>104</volume>
<fpage>13839</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13844</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.0706386104</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17699623</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bailey</surname><given-names>T. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Misleh</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W. W.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>MEME: discovering and analyzing DNA and protein sequence motifs.</article-title>
<source><italic>Nucleic Acids Res.</italic></source>
<volume>34</volume>
<fpage>W369</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>W373</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/nar/gkl198</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16845028</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Barrett</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Troup</surname><given-names>D. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wilhite</surname><given-names>S. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ledoux</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Evangelista</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>I. F.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>NCBI GEO: archive for functional genomics data sets&#x02013;10 years on.</article-title>
<source><italic>Nucleic Acids Res.</italic></source>
<volume>39</volume>
<fpage>D1005</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>D1010</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/nar/gkq1184</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21097893</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Busk</surname><given-names>P. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pag&#x000e8;s</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1998</year>). <article-title>Regulation of abscisic acid-induced transcription.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Mol. Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>37</volume>
<fpage>425</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>435</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/A:1006058700720</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9617810</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lou</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Identification of differentially expressed genes and small molecule drugs for the treatment of tendinopathy using microarray analysis.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol Med Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>11</volume>
<fpage>3047</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3054</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2014.12.066</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25502513</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Calzadilla</surname><given-names>P. I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Maiale</surname><given-names>S. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruiz</surname><given-names>O. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Escaray</surname><given-names>F. J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Transcriptome response mediated by cold stress in <italic>Lotus japonicas</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Plant. Sci.</italic></source>
<volume>7</volume>:<issue>374</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpls.2016.00374</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Campo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Baldrich</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Messeguer</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lalanne</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Coca</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>San Segundo</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of a calcium-dependent protein kinase confers salt and drought tolerance in rice by preventing membrane lipid peroxidation.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>165</volume>
<fpage>688</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>704</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.113.230268</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24784760</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Campos</surname><given-names>P. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Quartin</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ramalho</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nunes</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>Electrolyte leakage and lipid degradation account for cold sensitivity in leaves of <italic>Coffea</italic> sp. plants.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>160</volume>
<fpage>283</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>292</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1078/0176-1617-00833</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12749085</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ronald</surname><given-names>P. C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>The rice oligonucleotide array database: an atlas of rice gene expression.</article-title>
<source><italic>Rice (NY)</italic></source>
<volume>5</volume>
<issue>17</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1939-8433-5-17</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>W. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>T. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>R. L.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>PlantPAN: plant promoter analysis navigator, for identifying combinatorial cis-regulatory elements with distance constraint in plant gene groups.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMC Genomics</italic></source>
<volume>9</volume>:<issue>561</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-9-561</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Charlton</surname><given-names>A. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Donarski</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Harrison</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jones</surname><given-names>S. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Godward</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Oehlschlager</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Responses of the pea (<italic>Pisum sativum</italic> L.) leaf metabolome to drought stress assessed by nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy.</article-title>
<source><italic>Metabolomics</italic></source>
<volume>4</volume>
<fpage>312</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>327</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11306-008-0128-0</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chawade</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lindl&#x000f6;f</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Olsson</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Olsson</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Global expression profiling of low temperature induced genes in the chilling tolerant japonica rice Jumli Marshi.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>8</volume>:<issue>e81729</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0081729</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chinnusamy</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ohta</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kanrar</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>B. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Agarwal</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>ICE1: a regulator of cold-induced transcriptome and freezing tolerance in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Genes Dev.</italic></source>
<volume>17</volume>
<fpage>1043</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1054</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1101/gad.1077503</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12672693</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chou</surname><given-names>W. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>L. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yeh</surname><given-names>C. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>C. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>S. J.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Divergence of the expression and subcellular localization of CCR4-associated factor 1 (CAF1) deadenylase proteins in <italic>Oryza sativa</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Mol. Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>85</volume>
<fpage>443</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>458</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11103-014-0196-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24805883</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chow</surname><given-names>C. N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>H. Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>N. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chien</surname><given-names>C. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>H. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>T. Y.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>PlantPAN 2.0: an update of plant promoter analysis navigator for reconstructing transcriptional regulatory networks in plants.</article-title>
<source><italic>Nucleic Acids Res.</italic></source>
<volume>44</volume>
<fpage>D1154</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>D1160</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/nar/gkv1035</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26476450</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chu</surname><given-names>V. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gottardo</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Raftery</surname><given-names>A. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bumgarner</surname><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yeung</surname><given-names>K. Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>MeV+R: using MeV as a graphical user interface for Bioconductor applications in microarray analysis.</article-title>
<source><italic>Genome Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>9</volume>:<issue>R118</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/gb-2008-9-7-r118</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B22"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gong</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>OST1 kinase modulates freezing tolerance by enhancing ICE1 stability in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Dev. Cell</italic></source>
<volume>32</volume>
<fpage>278</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>289</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.devcel.2014.12.023</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25669882</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B23"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>C. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Agarwal</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>J. K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>The negative regulator of plant cold responses, HOS1 is a RING E3 ligase that mediates the ubiquitination and degradation of ICE1.</article-title>
<source><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A.</italic></source>
<volume>103</volume>
<fpage>8281</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8286</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.0602874103</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16702557</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dubouzet</surname><given-names>J. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sakuma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kasuga</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dubouzet</surname><given-names>E. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title><italic>OsDREB</italic> genes in rice, <italic>Oryza sativa</italic> L., encode transcription activators that function in drought-, high-salt- and cold-responsive gene expression.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>33</volume>
<fpage>751</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>763</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1365-313X.2003.01661.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12609047</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B25"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Frey</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Klotz</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nick</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>A kinesin with calponin-homology domain is involved in premitotic nuclear migration.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Exp. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>61</volume>
<fpage>3423</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3437</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/jxb/erq164</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20566563</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>De novo transcriptome sequencing and gene expression profiling of <italic>Elymus nutans</italic> under cold stress.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMC Genomics</italic></source>
<volume>17</volume>:<issue>870</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12864-016-3222-0</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fursova</surname><given-names>O. V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pogorelko</surname><given-names>G. V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tarasov</surname><given-names>V. A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Identification of ICE2 a gene involved in cold acclimation which determines freezing tolerance in <italic>Arabidopsis thaliana</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Gene</italic></source>
<volume>429</volume>
<fpage>98</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>103</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2008.10.016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19026725</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B28"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ge</surname><given-names>L. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chao</surname><given-names>D. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>M. Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>J. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>H. X.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of the trehalose-6-phosphate phosphatase gene OsTPP1 confers stress tolerance in rice and results in the activation of stress responsive genes.</article-title>
<source><italic>Planta</italic></source>
<volume>228</volume>
<fpage>191</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>201</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00425-008-0729-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18365248</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B29"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hakata</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kuroda</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ohsumi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirose</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Muramatsu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of a rice TIFY gene increases grain size through enhanced accumulation of carbohydrates in the stem.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biosci. Biotechnol. Biochem.</italic></source>
<volume>76</volume>
<fpage>2129</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2134</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1271/bbb.120545</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23132589</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B30"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jeon</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>OsWRKY42 represses OsMT1d and induces reactive oxygen species and leaf senescence in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Cells</italic></source>
<volume>37</volume>
<fpage>532</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>539</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.14348/molcells.2014.0128</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25081037</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B31"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>W. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>Y. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Moon</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Genome-wide identification and extensive analysis of rice-endosperm preferred genes using reference expression database.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>60</volume>
<fpage>249</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>258</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12374-016-0552-z</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B32"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>A TFIIIA-type zinc finger protein confers multiple abiotic stress tolerances in transgenic rice (<italic>Oryza sativa</italic> L.).</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Mol. Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>80</volume>
<fpage>337</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>350</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11103-012-9955-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22930448</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B33"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>S. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>D. Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bao</surname><given-names>Y. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z. F.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Increased tolerance of rice to cold, drought and oxidative stresses mediated by the overexpression of a gene that encodes the zinc finger protein ZFP245.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun.</italic></source>
<volume>389</volume>
<fpage>556</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>561</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2009.09.032</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19751706</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B34"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>M. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>L. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>A novel rice C2H2-type zinc finger protein lacking DLN-box/EAR-motif plays a role in salt tolerance.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biochim. Biophys. Acta</italic></source>
<volume>1769</volume>
<fpage>220</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>227</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bbaexp.2007.02.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17434609</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B35"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ishiguro</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1994</year>). <article-title>Characterization of a cDNA encoding a novel DNA-binding protein, SPF1 that recognizes SP8 sequences in the 5&#x02019; upstream regions of genes coding for sporamin and &#x003b2;-amylase from sweet potato.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Gen. Genet.</italic></source>
<volume>244</volume>
<fpage>563</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>571</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00282746</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7969025</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B36"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Katsura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Maruyama</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Taji</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Seki</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>Functional analysis of rice DREB1/CBF-type transcription factors involved in cold-responsive gene expression in transgenic rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>47</volume>
<fpage>141</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>153</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/pcp/pci230</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16284406</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B37"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Iwamoto</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Higo</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Takano</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Circadian clock- and phytochrome-regulated Dof-like gene, Rdd1 is associated with grain size in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Environ.</italic></source>
<volume>3</volume>
<fpage>592</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>603</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3040.2009.01954.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B38"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Rice tissue-specific promoters and condition-dependent promoters for effective translational application.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Integr. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>57</volume>
<fpage>913</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>924</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jipb.12362</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25882130</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B39"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>J. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>P. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>C. M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>The E3 ubiquitin ligase HOS1 regulates <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> flowering by mediating CONSTANS degradation under cold stress.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Biol. Chem.</italic></source>
<volume>287</volume>
<fpage>43277</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>43287</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1074/jbc.M112.394338</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23135282</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B40"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Application of MapMan and RiceNet drives systematic analyses of the early heat stress transcriptome in rice seedlings.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>55</volume>
<fpage>436</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>449</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12374-012-0270-0</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B41"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ronald</surname><given-names>P. C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008b</year>). <article-title>Towards a better bowl of rice: assigning function to tens of thousands of rice genes.</article-title>
<source><italic>Nat. Rev. Genet.</italic></source>
<volume>9</volume>
<fpage>91</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>101</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nrg2286</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18160965</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B42"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dardick</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bartley</surname><given-names>L. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Phetsom</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Canlas</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2008a</year>). <article-title>Refinement of light-responsive transcript lists using rice oligonucleotide arrays: evaluation of gene-redundancy.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>3</volume>:<issue>e3337</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0003337</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B43"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Y. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schreiber</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Franke</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>Wax-deficient anther1 is involved in cuticle and wax production in rice anther walls and is required for pollen development.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>18</volume>
<fpage>3015</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3032</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.106.042044</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17138699</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B44"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Y. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>Rice Undeveloped Tapetum1 is a major regulator of early tapetum development.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>17</volume>
<fpage>2705</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2722</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.105.034090</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16141453</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B45"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>K. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Giong</surname><given-names>H. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nguyen</surname><given-names>M. X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Koh</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Genome-wide identification and functional analysis of genes expressed ubiquitously in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Plant</italic></source>
<volume>8</volume>
<fpage>276</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>289</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.molp.2014.10.013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25624149</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B46"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kaneda</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Taga</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Takai</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Iwano</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Matsui</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Takayama</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>The transcription factor OsNAC4 is a key positive regulator of plant hypersensitive cell death.</article-title>
<source><italic>EMBO J.</italic></source>
<volume>28</volume>
<fpage>926</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>936</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/emboj.2009.39</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19229294</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B47"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kasuga</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shinozaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamaguchi-Shinozaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>A combination of the <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> DREB1A gene and stress-inducible rd29A promoter improved drought- and low-temperature stress tolerance in tobacco by gene transfer.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>45</volume>
<issue>346</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/pcp/pch037</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B48"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>C. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vo</surname><given-names>K. T. X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nguyen</surname><given-names>C. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jeong</surname><given-names>D. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Functional analysis of a cold-responsive rice WRKY gene, OsWRKY71.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Biotechnol. Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>
<fpage>13</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>23</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11816-015-0383-2</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B49"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kiribuchi</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sugimori</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Takeda</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Otani</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Onodera</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>RERJ1 a jasmonic acid-responsive gene from rice, encodes a basic helix-loop-helix protein.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun.</italic></source>
<volume>325</volume>
<fpage>857</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>863</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2004.10.126</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15541369</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B50"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Koiwai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tagiri</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Katoh</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Katoh</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ichikawa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Minami</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>RING-H2 type ubiquitin ligase EL5 is involved in root development through the maintenance of cell viability in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>51</volume>
<fpage>92</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>104</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-313X.2007.03120.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17559513</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B51"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kudo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Makita</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kojima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tokunaga</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sakakibara</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Cytokinin activity of cis-zeatin and phenotypic alterations induced by overexpression of putative cis-zeatin-O-glucosyltransferase in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>160</volume>
<fpage>319</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>331</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.112.196733</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22811434</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B52"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>An</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-R.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Ectopic expression of OsSta2 enhances salt stress tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Plant Sci.</italic></source>
<volume>8</volume>:<issue>316</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpls.2017.00316</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B53"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Aye</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Over-expression of dehydrin gene, OsDhn1 improves drought and salt stress tolerance through scavenging of reactive oxygen species in rice (<italic>Oryza sativa</italic> L.).</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>57</volume>
<fpage>383</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>393</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12374-014-0487-1</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B54"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>Y. I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Osakabe</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Endo</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nishizawa-Yokoi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Saika</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of OsRecQl4 and/or OsExo1 enhances DSB-induced homologous recombination in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>53</volume>
<fpage>2142</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2152</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/pcp/pcs155</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23161853</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B55"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>S.-C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.-Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.-J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>S.-K.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>Trapping and characterization of cold-responsive genes from T-DNA tagging lines in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Sci.</italic></source>
<volume>166</volume>
<fpage>69</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>79</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.plantsci.2003.08.008</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B56"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chong</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of a homopeptide repeat-containing bHLH protein gene (OrbHLH001) from Dongxiang wild rice confers freezing and salt tolerance in transgenic <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>29</volume>
<fpage>977</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>986</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00299-010-0883-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20559833</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B57"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>H. W.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>Arabidopsis PLD zeta 2 regulates vesicle trafficking and is required for auxin response.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>19</volume>
<fpage>281</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>295</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.106.041426</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17259265</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B58"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Quan</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>G. Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>OsDREB1 gene from rice enhances cold tolerance in tobacco.</article-title>
<source><italic>Tsinghua Sci. Technol.</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>
<fpage>478</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>483</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S1007-0214(05)70103-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B59"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>bZIP transcription factor OsbZIP52/RISBZ5: a potential negative regulator of cold and drought stress response in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Planta</italic></source>
<volume>235</volume>
<fpage>1157</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1169</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00425-011-1564-z</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22189955</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B60"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>OsWRKY71 a rice transcription factor, is involved in rice defense response.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>164</volume>
<fpage>969</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>979</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jplph.2006.07.006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16919842</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B61"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>OsDOG, a gibberellin-induced A20/AN1 zinc-finger protein, negatively regulates gibberellin-mediated cell elongation in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>168</volume>
<fpage>1098</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1105</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jplph.2010.12.013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21316795</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B62"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lo</surname><given-names>S. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>S. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>K. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hsing</surname><given-names>Y. I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zeevaart</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L. J.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>A novel class of gibberellin 2-oxidases control semidwarfism, tillering, and root development in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>20</volume>
<fpage>2603</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2618</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.108.060913</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18952778</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B63"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mar&#x000e8;</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mazzucotelli</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Crosatti</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Francia</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Stanca</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cattivelli</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>Hv-WRKY38: a new transcription factor involved in cold-and drought-response in barley.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Mol. Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>55</volume>
<fpage>399</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>416</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11103-004-0906-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15604689</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B64"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mei</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sheng</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>Inducible overexpression of a rice allene oxide synthase gene increases the endogenous jasmonic acid level, PR gene expression, and host resistance to fungal infection.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Plant Microbe Interact.</italic></source>
<volume>19</volume>
<fpage>1127</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1137</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1094/MPMI-19-1127</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17022177</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B65"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Furumoto</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Cold signaling and cold response in plants.</article-title>
<source><italic>Int. J. Mol. Sci.</italic></source>
<volume>14</volume>
<fpage>5312</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5337</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/ijms14035312</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23466881</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B66"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>J. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoo</surname><given-names>C. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Stirm</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Miura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>SIZ1-mediated sumoylation of ICE1 controls CBF3/DREB1A expression and freezing tolerance in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>19</volume>
<fpage>1403</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1414</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.106.048397</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17416732</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B67"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mohanty</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Krishnan</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Swarup</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bajic</surname><given-names>V. B.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>Detection and preliminary analysis of motifs in promoters of anaerobically induced genes of different plant species.</article-title>
<source><italic>Ann. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>96</volume>
<fpage>669</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>681</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/aob/mci219</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16027132</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B68"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mohanty</surname><given-names>J. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jaffe</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schulman</surname><given-names>E. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Raible</surname><given-names>D. G.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1997</year>). <article-title>A highly sensitive fluorescent micro-assay of H2O2 release from activated human leukocytes using a dihydroxyphenoxazine derivative.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Immunol. Methods</italic></source>
<volume>202</volume>
<fpage>133</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>141</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0022-1759(96)00244-X</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9107302</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B69"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mori</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nomura</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ooka</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ishizaka</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yokota</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sugimoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2002</year>). <article-title>Isolation and characterization of a rice dwarf mutant with a defect in brassinosteroid biosynthesis.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>130</volume>
<fpage>1152</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1161</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.007179</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12427982</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B70"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Murashige</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Skoog</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1962</year>). <article-title>A revised medium for rapid growth and bio assays with tobacco tissue cultures.</article-title>
<source><italic>Physiol. Plant.</italic></source>
<volume>15</volume>
<fpage>473</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>497</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1399-3054.1962.tb08052.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B71"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ni</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>OsIAA23-mediated auxin signaling defines postembryonic maintenance of QC in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>68</volume>
<fpage>433</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>442</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-313X.2011.04698.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21736653</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B72"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ogawa</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hanada</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamauchi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kuwahara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kamiya</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamaguchi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>Gibberellin biosynthesis and response during Arabidopsis seed germination.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>15</volume>
<fpage>1591</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1604</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.011650</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12837949</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B73"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ono</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Izawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chua</surname><given-names>N. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shimamoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1996</year>). <article-title>The rab16B promoter of rice contains two distinct abscisic acid-responsive elements.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>112</volume>
<fpage>483</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>491</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.112.2.483</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8883374</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B74"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Piston</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Uauy</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Langston</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Labavitch</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dubcovsky</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Down-regulation of four putative arabinoxylan feruloyl transferase genes from family PF02458 reduces ester-linked ferulate content in rice cell walls.</article-title>
<source><italic>Planta</italic></source>
<volume>231</volume>
<fpage>677</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>691</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00425-009-1077-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20012086</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B75"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>Y. Q.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>Rice ethylene-response AP2/ERF factor OsEATB restricts internode elongation by down-regulating a gibberellin biosynthetic gene.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>157</volume>
<fpage>216</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>228</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.111.179945</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21753115</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B76"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sakuma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y. Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shinozaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>Cloning and functional analysis of a novel DREB1/CBF transcription factor involved in cold-responsive gene expression in <italic>Zea mays</italic> L.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>45</volume>
<fpage>1042</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1052</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/pcp/pch118</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15356330</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B77"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qiu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Rice gene network inferred from expression profiling of plants overexpressing OsWRKY13 a positive regulator of disease resistance.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Plant</italic></source>
<volume>1</volume>
<fpage>538</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>551</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/mp/ssn012</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19825559</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B78"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>D. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rao</surname><given-names>Y. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>L. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xun</surname><given-names>Q. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Z. Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>H. P.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>The pleiotropic ABNORMAL FLOWER AND DWARF1 affects plant height, floral development and grain yield in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Integr. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>58</volume>
<fpage>529</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>539</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jipb.12441</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26486996</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B79"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rerksiri</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Expression and promoter analysis of six heat stress-inducible genes in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Sci. World J.</italic></source>
<volume>2013</volume>
<fpage>397</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>401</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2013/397401</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B80"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saijo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hata</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kyozuka</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shimamoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Izui</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2000</year>). <article-title>Over-expression of a single Ca2+-dependent protein kinase confers both cold and salt/drought tolerance on rice plants.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>23</volume>
<fpage>319</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>327</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1365-313x.2000.00787.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10929125</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B81"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sakuma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dubouzet</surname><given-names>J. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Abe</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shinozaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamaguchi-Shinozaki</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2002</year>). <article-title>DNA-binding specificity of the ERF/AP2 domain of <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> DREBs, transcription factors involved in dehydration- and cold-inducible gene expression.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun.</italic></source>
<volume>290</volume>
<fpage>998</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1009</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/bbrc.2001.6299</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11798174</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B82"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schmidt</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schippers</surname><given-names>J. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mieulet</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Obata</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fernie</surname><given-names>A. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guiderdoni</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>MULTIPASS, a rice R2R3-type MYB transcription factor, regulates adaptive growth by integrating multiple hormonal pathways.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>76</volume>
<fpage>258</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>273</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/tpj.12286</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23855375</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B83"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Seo</surname><given-names>J.-S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Joo</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>M.-J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y.-K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nahm</surname><given-names>B. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>S. I.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>OsbHLH148 a basic helix-loop-helix protein, interacts with OsJAZ proteins in a jasmonate signaling pathway leading to drought tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>65</volume>
<fpage>907</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>921</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-313X.2010.04477.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21332845</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B84"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shakiba</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names>J. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jodari</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Duke</surname><given-names>S. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Baldo</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Korniliev</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Genetic architecture of cold tolerance in rice (<italic>Oryza sativa</italic>) determined through high resolution genome-wide analysis.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>12</volume>:<issue>e0172133</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0172133</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B85"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shan</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Transcriptome profile analysis of maize seedlings in response to high-salinity, drought and cold stresses by deep sequencing.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Mol. Biol. Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>31</volume>:<issue>1485</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11105-013-0622-z</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B86"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>You</surname><given-names>M. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jeung</surname><given-names>J. U.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>OsMPK3 is a TEY-type rice MAPK in Group C and phosphorylates OsbHLH65 a transcription factor binding to the E-box element.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>33</volume>
<fpage>1343</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1353</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00299-014-1620-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24777821</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B87"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>C. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hsieh</surname><given-names>T. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>C. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tseng</surname><given-names>T. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>S. M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>A novel MYBS3-dependent pathway confers cold tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>153</volume>
<fpage>145</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>158</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.110.153015</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20130099</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B88"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>A novel MYB transcription factor, GmMYBj1 from soybean confers drought and cold tolerance in <italic>Arabidopsis thaliana</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Gene</italic></source>
<volume>538</volume>
<fpage>46</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>55</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.gene.2014.01.024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24440241</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B89"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>S. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>S. Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bao</surname><given-names>Y. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Functional analysis of a novel Cys2/His2-type zinc finger protein involved in salt tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Exp. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>61</volume>
<fpage>2807</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2818</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/jxb/erq120</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20460361</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B90"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sutoh</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamauchi</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>Two <italic>cis</italic>-acting elements necessary and sufficient for gibberellin-upregulated proteinase expression in rice seeds.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>34</volume>
<fpage>635</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>645</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1365-313X.2003.01753.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12787245</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B91"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>Over-expression of JcDREB, a putative AP2/EREBP domain-containing transcription factor gene in woody biodiesel plant Jatropha curcas, enhances salt and freezing tolerance in transgenic <italic>Arabidopsis thaliana</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Sci.</italic></source>
<volume>181</volume>
<fpage>623</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>631</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.plantsci.2011.06.014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21958703</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B92"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kou</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>OsWRKY45 alleles play different roles in abscisic acid signalling and salt stress tolerance but similar roles in drought and cold tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Exp. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>62</volume>
<fpage>4863</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4874</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/jxb/err144</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21725029</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B93"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Terada</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakayama</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Iwabuchi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shimamoto</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1993</year>). <article-title>A wheat histone H3 promoter confers cell division-dependent and -independent expression of the gus A gene in transgenic rice plants.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>3</volume>
<fpage>241</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>252</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8220444</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B94"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tsutsui</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Asada</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sako</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sonoda</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>DEAR1 a transcriptional repressor of DREB protein that mediates plant defense and freezing stress responses in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Res.</italic></source>
<volume>122</volume>
<issue>633</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10265-009-0252-6</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B95"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ueguchi-Tanaka</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ashikar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakajima</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Itoh</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Katoh</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>GIBBERELLIN INSENSITIVE DWARF1 encodes a soluble receptor for gibberellin.</article-title>
<source><italic>Nature</italic></source>
<volume>437</volume>
<fpage>693</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>698</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nature04028</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16193045</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B96"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Urbanczyk-Wochniak</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Usadel</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Thimm</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nunes-Nesi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Carrari</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Davy</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>Conversion of MapMan to allow the analysis of transcript data from <italic>Solanaceous</italic> species: effects of genetic and environmental alterations in energy metabolism in the leaf.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Mol. Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>60</volume>
<fpage>773</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>792</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11103-005-5772-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16649112</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B97"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Usadel</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Blasing</surname><given-names>O. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gibon</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Retzlaff</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hoehne</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gunther</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Multilevel genomic analysis of the response of transcripts, enzyme activities and metabolites in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> rosettes to a progressive decrease of temperature in the non-freezing range.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell Environ.</italic></source>
<volume>31</volume>
<fpage>518</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>547</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3040.2007.01763.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18088337</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B98"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Usadel</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nagel</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Thimm</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name><name><surname>Redestig</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Blaesing</surname><given-names>O. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Palacios-Rojas</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>Extension of the visualization tool MapMan to allow statistical analysis of arrays, display of corresponding genes, and comparison with known responses.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>138</volume>
<fpage>1195</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1204</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.105.060459</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16009995</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B99"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vannini</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Locatelli</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bracale</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Magnani</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Marsoni</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Osnato</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of the rice Osmyb4 gene increases chilling and freezing tolerance of <italic>Arabidopsis</italic> thaliana plants.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>37</volume>
<fpage>115</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>127</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1365-313X.2003.01938.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14675437</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B100"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Verma</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ravindran</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>P. P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Plant hormone-mediated regulation of stress responses.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMC Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>16</volume>:<issue>86</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12870-016-0771-y</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B101"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wan</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Quan</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>Transcriptional activation of OsDERF1 in OsERF3 and OsAP2-39 negatively modulates ethylene synthesis and drought tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>6</volume>:<issue>e25216</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0025216</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B102"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Down-regulation of OsSPX1 causes high sensitivity to cold and oxidative stresses in rice seedlings.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>8</volume>:<issue>e81849</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0081849</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B103"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Genome-wide association mapping of cold tolerance genes at the seedling stage in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Rice</italic></source>
<volume>9</volume>:<issue>61</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12284-016-0133-2</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B104"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hou</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>A novel cold-inducible gene from Pak-choi (<italic>Brassica campestris</italic> ssp. chinensis), BcWRKY46 enhances the cold, salt and dehydration stress tolerance in transgenic tobacco.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Biol. Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>39</volume>
<fpage>4553</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4564</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11033-011-1245-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21938429</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B105"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>A novel mitogen-activated protein kinase gene in maize (<italic>Zea mays</italic>), ZmMPK3 is involved in response to diverse environmental cues.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Integr. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>52</volume>
<fpage>442</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>452</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1744-7909.2010.00906.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20537040</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B106"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Welti</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>Profiling lipid changes in plant response to low temperatures.</article-title>
<source><italic>Physiol. Plant.</italic></source>
<volume>126</volume>
<fpage>90</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>96</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1399-3054.2006.00622.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B107"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Q. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>C. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>H. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>Y. M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Global transcriptome profiles of <italic>Camellia sinensis</italic> during cold acclimation.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMC Genomics</italic></source>
<volume>14</volume>:<issue>415</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-14-415</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B108"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>Isolation and characterization of a cold-induced DREB gene from <italic>Aloe vera</italic> L.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Mol. Biol. Report.</italic></source>
<volume>25</volume>
<fpage>121</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>132</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11105-007-0014-3</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B109"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W. X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>CsWRKY2 a novel WRKY gene from <italic>Camellia sinensis</italic>, is involved in cold and drought stress responses.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biol. Plant.</italic></source>
<volume>60</volume>
<issue>443</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s10535-016-0618-2</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B110"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>X. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>H. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>Y. X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>J. X.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>A rice transcription factor OsbHLH1 is involved in cold stress response.</article-title>
<source><italic>Theor. Appl. Genet.</italic></source>
<volume>107</volume>
<fpage>1402</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1409</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00122-003-1378-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12920519</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B111"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruan</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Rice SPX1 and SPX2 inhibit phosphate starvation responses through interacting with PHR2 in a phosphate-dependent manner.</article-title>
<source><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A.</italic></source>
<volume>111</volume>
<fpage>14953</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>14958</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.1404680111</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25271318</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B112"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>L. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Identification of root-preferential transcription factors in rice by analyzing GUS expression patterns of T-DNA tagging lines.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>60</volume>
<fpage>268</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>277</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12374-016-0597-z</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B113"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ke</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Global transcriptome profiles of &#x02018;Meyer&#x02019; zoysiagrass in response to cold stress.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>:<issue>e0131153</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0131153</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B114"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>ERF protein JERF1 that transcriptionally modulates the expression of abscisic acid biosynthesis-related gene enhances the tolerance under salinity and cold in tobacco.</article-title>
<source><italic>Planta</italic></source>
<volume>226</volume>
<fpage>815</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>825</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00425-007-0528-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17479283</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B115"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wuriyanghan</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>W. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lei</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y. F.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>The ethylene receptor ETR2 delays floral transition and affects starch accumulations in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>21</volume>
<fpage>1473</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1494</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.108.065391</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19417056</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B116"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xiang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Man</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of a ItICE1 gene from <italic>Isatis tinctoria</italic> enhances cold tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Breed.</italic></source>
<volume>32</volume>
<fpage>617</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>628</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11032-013-9894-0</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B117"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>A. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>H. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhuang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>R. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Expression and function of a modified AP2/ERF transcription factor from <italic>Brassica napus</italic> enhances cold tolerance in transgenic <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Biotechnol.</italic></source>
<volume>53</volume>
<fpage>198</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>206</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12033-012-9515-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22351429</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B118"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>Disease resistance and abiotic stress tolerance in rice are inversely modulated by an abscisic acid-inducible mitogen-activated protein kinase.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Cell</italic></source>
<volume>15</volume>
<fpage>745</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>759</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1105/tpc.008714</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12615946</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B119"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>The grapevine basic helix-loop-helix (bHLH) transcription factor positively modulates CBF-pathway and confers tolerance to cold-stress in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Biol. Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>41</volume>
<fpage>5329</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5342</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11033-014-3404-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24859977</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B120"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yaish</surname><given-names>M. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>El-Kereamy</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Beatty</surname><given-names>P. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Good</surname><given-names>A. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bi</surname><given-names>Y. M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>The APETALA-2-like transcription factor OsAP2&#x02013;39 controls key interactions between abscisic acid and gibberellin in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS Genet.</italic></source>
<volume>6</volume>:<issue>e1001098</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pgen.1001098</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B121"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yamaguchi</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kuroda</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamakawa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ashizawa</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirayae</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kurimoto</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Suppression of a phospholipase D gene, OsPLD beta 1 activates defense responses and increases disease resistance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol.</italic></source>
<volume>150</volume>
<fpage>308</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>319</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1104/pp.108.131979</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19286937</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B122"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yonemaru</surname><given-names>J.-I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yano</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>OGRO: the overview of functionally characterized Genes in Rice online database.</article-title>
<source><italic>Rice</italic></source>
<volume>5</volume>
<fpage>1</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>10</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1939-8433-5-26</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24764501</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B123"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>Y. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Z. X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>Y. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y. M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of an F-box protein gene reduces abiotic stress tolerance and promotes root growth in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mol. Plant</italic></source>
<volume>4</volume>
<fpage>190</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>197</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/mp/ssq066</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21059694</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B124"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>X. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W. H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>A R2R3-type MYB gene, OsMYB2 is involved in salt, cold, and dehydration tolerance in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Exp. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>63</volume>
<fpage>2541</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2556</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/jxb/err431</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22301384</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B125"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Comparative transcriptome analysis of shoots and roots of TNG67 and TCN1 rice seedlings under cold stress and following subsequent recovery: insights into metabolic pathways, phytohormones, and transcription Factors.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>:<issue>e0131391</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0131391</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B126"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yokotani</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tanabe</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chujo</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shimizu</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>OsWRKY76 is a rice transcriptional repressor playing opposite roles in blast disease resistance and cold stress tolerance.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Exp. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>64</volume>
<fpage>5085</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5097</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/jxb/ert298</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24043853</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B127"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>You</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zong</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ning</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>The SNAC1-targeted gene OsSRO1c modulates stomatal closure and oxidative stress tolerance by regulating hydrogen peroxide in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Exp. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>64</volume>
<fpage>569</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>583</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/jxb/ers349</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23202132</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B128"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ji</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>A single-repeat R3-MYB transcription factor MYBC1 negatively regulates freezing tolerance in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun.</italic></source>
<volume>394</volume>
<fpage>1018</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1023</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2010.03.114</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20331973</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B129"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Genome-wide gene expression profiling of introgressed indica rice alleles associated with seedling cold tolerance improvement in a japonica rice background.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMC Genomics</italic></source>
<volume>7</volume>:<issue>461</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-13-461</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B130"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ni</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>The C2H2-type zinc finger protein ZFP182 is involved in abscisic acid-induced antioxidant defense in rice.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Integr. Plant Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>54</volume>
<fpage>500</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>510</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1744-7909.2012.01135.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22693960</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B131"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Q. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>Y. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z. L.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Rice and cold stress: methods for its evaluation and summary of cold tolerance-related quantitative trait loci.</article-title>
<source><italic>Rice</italic></source>
<volume>7</volume>
<fpage>24</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>35</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12284-014-0024-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25279026</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B132"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Comparative transcriptome profiling of chilling stress responsiveness in two contrasting rice genotypes.</article-title>
<source><italic>PLoS ONE</italic></source>
<volume>7</volume>:<issue>e43274</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0043274</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B133"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>X. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>A. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Peng</surname><given-names>R. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hong</surname><given-names>Y. H.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Expression of a rice DREB1 gene, OsDREB1D, enhances cold and high-salt tolerance in transgenic <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>BMB Rep.</italic></source>
<volume>42</volume>
<fpage>486</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>492</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5483/BMBRep.2009.42.8.486</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19712584</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B134"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ling</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>CsWRKY46 a WRKY transcription factor from cucumber, confers cold resistance in transgenic-plant by regulating a set of cold-stress responsive genes in an ABA-dependent manner.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant Physiol. Biochem.</italic></source>
<volume>108</volume>
<fpage>478</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>487</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.plaphy.2016.08.013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27592172</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B135"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bai</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Molecular cloning and characterization of OsCHR4 a rice chromatin-remodeling factor required for early chloroplast development in adaxial mesophyll.</article-title>
<source><italic>Planta</italic></source>
<volume>236</volume>
<fpage>1165</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1176</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00425-012-1667-1</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22644768</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B136"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Global transcriptional profiling of a cold-tolerant rice variety under moderate cold stress reveals different cold stress response mechanisms.</article-title>
<source><italic>Physiol. Plant.</italic></source>
<volume>154</volume>
<fpage>381</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>394</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/ppl.12291</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25263631</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B137"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Overexpression of a NAC transcription factor enhances rice drought and salt tolerance.</article-title>
<source><italic>Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun.</italic></source>
<volume>379</volume>
<fpage>985</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>989</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2008.12.163</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19135985</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B138"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhi-guo</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Genome-wide characterisation of gene expression in rice leaf blades at 25&#x000b0;C and 30&#x000b0;C.</article-title>
<source><italic>Sci. World J.</italic></source>
<volume>7</volume>
<issue>917292</issue>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2014/917292</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B139"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Erb</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mao</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Silencing OsHI-LOX makes rice more susceptible to chewing herbivores, but enhances resistance to a phloem feeder.</article-title>
<source><italic>Plant J.</italic></source>
<volume>60</volume>
<fpage>638</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>648</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-313X.2009.03988.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19656341</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B140"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Verslues</surname><given-names>P. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>B. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhan</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Manabe</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>HOS10 encodes an R2R3-type MYB transcription factor essential for cold acclimation in plants.</article-title>
<source><italic>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A.</italic></source>
<volume>102</volume>
<fpage>9966</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>9971</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.0503960102</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15994234</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B141"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zou</surname><given-names>C. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>W. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>D. Q.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Male gametophyte-specific WRKY34 transcription factor negatively mediates cold stress tolerance of mature pollen in <italic>Arabidopsis</italic>.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Exp. Bot.</italic></source>
<volume>61</volume>
<fpage>3901</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3914</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/jxb/erq204</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20643804</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list id="DL1"><def-item><term>CREs</term><def><p><italic>cis</italic>-regulatory elements</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>DAG</term><def><p>days after germination</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>DEG</term><def><p>differentially expressed gene</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>FASTA</term><def><p>Fast Alignment Search Tool</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>GEO</term><def><p>gene expression omnibus</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>GO</term><def><p>gene ontology</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>GUS</term><def><p>&#x003b2;&#x003b2;-glucuronidase</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>KMC</term><def><p>K-means clustering</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>MAST</term><def><p>Motif Alignment and Search Tool</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>Mev</term><def><p>Multiple Experiment Viewer</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>MS</term><def><p>Murashige and Skoog</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>NCBI</term><def><p>National Center for Biotechnology Information</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>OGRO</term><def><p>overview of functionally characterized genes in rice online database</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>Ox</term><def><p>overexpression</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>PPI</term><def><p>protein&#x02013;protein interaction</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RGAP</term><def><p>Rice Genome Annotation Project</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>TF</term><def><p>transcription factor</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>TOMTOM</term><def><p>TF-binding site motifs found by the motif comparison tool</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>WT</term><def><p>wild type.</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary></back></article>